Welcome to use Git
like a pro live lessons.
My name is Ashima Ahuja. I have
over eight years of experience
as a front-end engineer
in the software industry.
My career includes
working with startups like Miro
and larger companies such
as Booking.com and Meta.
I enjoy sharing my knowledge through
online courses, workshops, and public speaking.
I have taken several
trainings and have spoken
at various conferences
aiming to contribute
to the tech community and support
others in their professional growth.
The main goal of this
course is to provide you
with a comprehensive understanding of Git,
covering everything from
basics to advanced topics
you will need in your day-to-day work.
I have pulled together information
based on industry standards and presented
in a way that makes both simple and
complex concepts easier to grasp.
Whether you are new to version control or
looking to enhance your existing skills,
this course is designed for you.
It aims to equip you with practical
knowledge to use Git effectively.
You will also learn to
confidently collaborate
with others in your development workflow.
The first lesson in this course
provides an overview of version control.
In this module, you gain a solid
understanding of Git and GitHub,
two widely used tools in the
software development world.
We cover the key Git terminologies,
learn how to set up and
install Git on your system,
and explore how to push code to
a remote repository on GitHub.
By the end of this lesson, you
should be able to create, clone,
and manage repositories with ease.
In the second lesson, we dive
deeper into the practical use of Git,
focusing on its workflow and commands.
The goal is to learn how to use Git,
both from the command line and
through the graphical user interface.
We explore how to add and
commit changes to a Git repository.
You are introduced to the Git log command,
which helps in
reviewing the previous commits.
This module covers how to fetch and
pull updates from a remote repository.
Additionally, we simplify
your workflow with Git aliases,
which help you create shortcuts
for frequently used commands.
Next lesson covers how to create
perfect commits and write clear
commit messages using the
conventional commits format,
ensuring a clean project history.
You will learn how to
amend commits and use the
git diff command to
review changes effectively.
After that, we move on to see how to undo
changes in Git commands like git checkout,
git restore, git reset, and git revert.
We are going to learn when and
how to use each of these commands
to revert and modify
changes safely in your project.
By the end, you should know how to
effectively recover from the mistakes.
Next, we will explore git branches,
understanding how they work and how to
manage them with commands like git branch.
We will also learn how to
rename and delete branches.
This lesson also covers usage of
tags for versioning and releases,
providing tools for more
organized project management.
Finally, we move to the most
important part of our day-to-day workflow.
We dive into merging and rebasing.
You are going to learn
the differences between
these two methods of integrating changes,
practice them, and discover
how to create pull requests.
And finally, we close the course with
some advanced Git concepts like stashing,
squashing commits,
performing an interactive rebase,
and using reflog to correct our mistakes.
Well, that's the basic plan of the course.
Thanks again for joining me in this live
lessons, and I hope you enjoy the course.