Welcome to Lesson 1, Getting Started.
First of all, this and some of
the following chapters are mainly
meant for those who are not
familiar or are very new to Git.
So if you're already
familiar with the basics of Git,
you may want to skip
through some of the concepts.
If not, this is a great place to start.
We start off this chapter by
learning about version control,
followed by understanding Git and
some important Git terminologies
that you're going to be
hearing a lot throughout the course.
Next, we do the Git setup,
create our first repository.
We then wrap up the lesson with a
quick summary, followed by an exercise.
Well, that's the plan for
this lesson. Let's get started.