Before we jump into the
world of Git and GitHub,
let's first talk about version control.
What is a version control?
So basically, whenever you're
working with digital files,
whether it's a doc file or any
programming file like Python or JS file,
you probably won't
finish all the work at once.
In that case, the software
you use to manage and track
changes in those files
is your version control.
To understand it better,
let's take an example.
Let's say I want to
create this git course.
So I started with a git course.doc
file and added my content there.
Next day, I wanted to make
some more changes to it,
so I copied this file and created
git course underscore v1.doc file.
During my final revision, I created
another copy, which is the final doc,
and added my final modifications there.
Now, why I was creating all those
files, why I was copying all those files,
and it is just to make
sure that I could go back
to the previous
version in case I need them.
Now, this approach technically works.
I'm able to track the changes in my files,
go back to the previous versions.
But let's say you're working on a
project with hundreds of files.
In that case, creating multiple files
for each of the file in the project,
it's not really scalable.
Although this idea makes sense,
but creating multiple files at work
can get really messy really fast.
Alternatively, what you
could have done is that you
can try to update the same
file over and over again,
but what if you want to go
back to the previous version
because there is some
bug in the new version?
Also, what if you want to work with
others, with your coworkers on the same file?
So we want a system which is robust
that allow us to work on the same file,
but also retain the
history of previous versions.
A version control
system is such system which
allow us to track changes within the same
file without creating multiple files and
also collaborate with others and much more.
A version control system
should also be distributed
in order to avoid any
single point of failure.
Git is one of the most popular
version control systems that we have.
It allows us to track
changes within the same file and
also allows us to
collaborate with our coworkers.
It's free and open source and
downloadable to your own local computer.