In the previous
section, we talked about Git,
that Git is the most popular open
version control system that tracks changes
within the same file and also allow
us to collaborate with our peers.
Now, throughout the course, you will
notice that git with small g getting used,
and also the git with capital G
is getting used interchangeably.
We use Git with capital G for the project,
whereas the Git with
small g refers to the actual
software and is used in all the commands.
Now we know what is Git,
let's also talk about GitHub.
You know that you can use
Git completely free on your
local computer to track
the changes in your files.
So it's just a software which you
can download and get started with it.
However, if you want your project
to be hosted over the internet,
you need a hosting service like
GitHub or GitLab or Bitbucket.
All the companies use their own
hosting platforms. Some of them use GitLab,
some of them use Bitbucket.
They are the most popular ones.
So GitHub is owned by Microsoft.
It's a hosting provider
that provides platform for
developers to store their
Git repositories online,
collaborate with others, and
also manage the code contributions.
A project hosted on
GitHub acts as the main
source for everyone
working on that project,
which means that everyone
who is working on that project
would read and write
into the same project.
Also, GitHub provides graphical
user interface for many Git features,
like merging issues or viewing commits,
and there are many more such features.
A lot of people confuse
between Git and GitHub,
but both are totally separate things.
Git is not the same thing as GitHub.
Git is basically an open
source version control software,
which you can download it in your
computer and start tracking your files.
So GitHub is a hosting platform for
the files which are managed by Git.
Basically, you have your
project on your local.
If you want to host it on the internet,
then you can leverage
GitHub as a hosting platform.