While working with Git, you will
come across many Git terminologies.
The first one we will
talk about is repository.
So basically, when we
set up Git in our project,
it creates a .git
folder inside the project.
The .git folder is what will do all the
versioning and file tracking for you.
A project with .git folder
inside it is referred as repository.
To recap, the repository is nothing but
your project with .git folder inside it.
The .git folder does all the file
tracking, and if this folder is deleted,
all the versioning and
tracking will be lost.
Next terminology we
will talk about is remote.
So we already talked about that
you have a project on your local,
but you want to host it
on the internet because
you want to collaborate with
your peers, with your coworkers.
So in that case, when you host
your project to the internet,
it refers to as remote server.
This server can be of GitHub, it can
be of GitLab, or it can be Bitbucket.
Third terminology which we
are going to discuss is origin.
You will hear this
terminology a lot, a lot, many times.
So basically, now you have your
project hosted on a remote server.
In order to read and write into
that project, you need a URL,
which is going to be your remote
repository URL. This URL is really long,
and if you have to read and write
into it, we have to write the whole URL.
So what Git provides us is with
an alias, which is called origin.
Origin is just an alias, which we
will use for the remote repo URL.
So that whenever you want to
read or write into the repository,
you don't have to write the entire URL,
but you can simply use origin