So let's install Git on your computer.
The installation process is slightly
different depending on your operating system.
For the Mac and Linux users,
Git comes already pre-installed.
In order to verify this, you
can simply type in your terminal,
Git hyphen hyphen version,
and it will tell you which version
of Git is installed on your computer.
Like for example, if I go to my
terminal and I do Git hyphen hyphen version,
It tells me that I have
2.32.1 Git installed.
But if you want to
update or reinstall Git,
you can do so by simply selecting macOS
or Linux links on the official Git website.
I have already provided a link here,
so just go to the website and
click on macOS and download it.
For the Windows users, you can also
download Git from the same official website,
and just instead of Mac, select Windows.
The installation is quite straightforward.
Just that on the screen which
asks you to select the text editor,
there will be Vim selected by default.
You can change it to any other text editor,
like here in two of the cores, I
would be using Visual Studio Code.
So you can change it to
VS Code if you want to,
or any other editor
which you prefer to use.
So we have Git installed. Next step
is getting your text editor installed.
Since we would be creating and
editing files throughout this course,
I would suggest you to
download Visual Studio Code.
I have provided the link
for Visual Studio Code,
so feel free to download
it into your computer.
You can also follow along with any
other text editor, whichever you prefer,
Sublime, Atom, or IntelliJ,
but I would be using Visual
Studio Code throughout the course.
After installing Git and after
having our text editor set up,
the next step is to have a GitHub account.
Note that whenever you
create the GitHub account,
copy the username and your email
address because you would be using
this username and email address
when you configure Git locally.
So make sure you have
noted the username and email
address which you have
registered with the GitHub.
Now to create an
account, go to www.github.com.
So just go to github.com.
And we'll click on Sign Up.
Enter your email.
Please note down the email
which you used to register with
it because we would need it
for the Git configuration.
Create a password.
Click on Continue.
Enter the username. Also make sure you
have noted down the username as well.
You can simply click on Continue,
verify your account, and let's submit.
So we are almost done. You will receive
a code on your email. Just fill it up,
and that's everything about
the registration with GitHub.