Now that we have installed Git,
we have installed our text editor,
and we also have set
up our GitHub account,
next thing we need to do is
to do some Git configurations.
First of all, check that if you already
have Git installed with this command,
git hyphen hyphen version.
So for the configurations, you
just need to add your name and email.
You can set it up using
git global config. For that,
you just need to run the
command git config hyphen
hyphen global user dot
name and type in your name.
Then git config hyphen hyphen global
user dot email and type in the email.
Now make sure the email address
which you type in here should be the
same email address which you
signed up into your GitHub account.
Another way to set up the configuration
is directly editing the git config file.
You can open the git config file
and add the name and email there.
Let's see how that looks
when we actually do it.
So let's first check what is
the config I already have.
You can do it using git
config hyphen hyphen list.
So I already have things set up. I
already have user dot email and user dot name.
But I can still override it with git
config hyphen hyphen global and user dot name.
And I can just simply do it.
Ashima, and now if I just
check if this is saved or not,
now you can see the user.name is Ashima.
Let me just set it back again. hyphen
hyphen global user.name And similarly,
for the email, you can
type in your email address.
Now, why we need to set the
name and email is because
Git needs to know your name and email when
you make any commit so
that it knows who committed
it and what was the email address used.
So without it, you won't be
able to make any commits in Git.
The another way which I showed you
was simply editing the git config file.
So you can open it vi using vim.gitconfig.
And here you can see that I
edited my email and there is a
name so you can just Press I and
start to type anything, and just save it.
Alternatively, if you are not
very comfortable with Vim commands,
I prefer to do it open
with Visual Studio Code.
So I just do code.gitconfig, and
this will open it in Coding editor.
So here, I have this
opened inside my coding editor,
and I can just change
it here, easily type it.
Let me also change back my name again.
So you can choose any of the
way which is comfortable for you.
You can do it via command line,
or you can also just open the git config
file and edit it directly into the file.
Sometimes you don't know
where your file is. So
usually with the Mac,
it is going to be here.
But in case you don't know where it is,
I think there is a command
which you can check git config.
Hyphen, hyphen, git config hyphen
hyphen list hyphen hyphen show origin.
And that will tell you where it
exists. Like, for example, in my case,
it existed inside
users, ashimahuja.gitconfig,
and that's why I was opening
it through tilt.gitconfig.
So if you want to know where your file
is, you can know the path from this command.