So let's create our first repository.
We already talked about
what a repository is.
It's just a project with
.git folder inside it.
This .git folder does all the tracking
of changes in your files in your project.
In order to start with a
repository, you need to initialize git.
So you need to do git init in the project.
It will create a .git
folder inside the project,
and git will start to
track your project files.
Sometimes you don't want Git
to track some of your files,
so you can add a file which is .gitignore,
and you can add all the files which
you don't want to track in that file.
Let's see how this looks in practice.
So let's start with the project. Let's
create a project. Let's call it Git course.
Let's move into the course directory.
And I will open it in my Visual
Studio Code using the command code dot.
If you're not able to do it like this,
then you need to go to the
Visual Studio Code and type
your install code command
and path shell command.
Once you install it, you would be able to
open any project with the code command.
Now let's here create a file.
Let's say I create a file1.txt,
and this is my first Git repository.
So right now, it's just a project with
one file. It's not a Git repository.
In order to make it a Git
repository, we need to do git init.
And as I do git init, let me do ls-a,
you will see the git folder is created.
I did ls-a because this is a hidden
folder, so it creates a .git folder,
which will do all your tracking,
and you can see that the
git is already initialized.
To verify it again, you
can run the status command.
So you can do git status.
And here, git tells you
that you are on branch main.
We'll talk about
branches later in the course,
but it says that you have
created one new file, file1.txt.
And there are no commits. We'll also be
talking about commits later in the course.
But basically, your project is
initialized as a Git repository. Now,
whatever changes you do in
this project is tracked by Git.
Now, sometimes you don't
want some files to be tracked.
So we talked about that
you can use gitignore file.
Such files can be your test files, or in
a lot of projects, it is node modules,
that you have node modules.
And Let's create
something here, datefn.js.
Let's say you have some node modules, and
I don't want to track The node modules.
So right now, if I do git status, then
git does tell me that you have two files,
like file one and also
this folder, node modules.
But what I want to tell Git
is ignore the node modules.
All the changes in node
modules, Git should not care about.
So I will create
gitignore. Yeah, just .gitignore.
And here, write node modules.
Now when I run my status
command, now we only have two files.
One is the gitignore file, which
I just created, and file1.txt,
but we don't have any node modules.
So this is how you can ignore some
files by adding them to gitignore.
There's often another folder which we
usually ignore is the coverage folder.
This includes your test coverage.
So you can also exclude it from the
git by just adding it to your gitignore.
There are a bunch of ways in
which you can generate your gitignore
file automatically because
there are some available templates.
I'm going to show you
one of the such template.
So just...
You can go to toptal.com
slash developer slash gitignore,
and here you can select the programming
language. Let's say I have selected React,
and now when I click on create,
it generates like a
template for the gitignore file.
So it means that if you are
working on a React project,
Those are the files which you
would add in the gitignore.
You can always change it
according to your requirements.
So this is also one
way you can generate it.
You can also do the
same for like the Python.
So let's say I have selected
Python as the programming language.
Now I say create, and it creates this.
There are a lot of files like
coverage folder, cache folder.
So it has created a template for us, and
then we can modify according to our needs.
Now we know how to create our repository.
Now let's also see how to
clone a public repository.
In order to clone a public
repository, you need to use git clone command.
Let's try to clone a public
repo, which is FlowByte React.
So I will go to their website.
So this is their website, and I want to
download this repo to my local computer.
So what I can do is just click on the
code and use HTTPS and copy the link here.
Now here you can use git clone
command and type the copied URL.
Once we hit enter, it
will Basically, download it,
and now you can see if we already have it.
So it's FlowByte React is already
created. I will just move to FlowByte React.
And you can open it again
in your Visual Studio Code,
and it will show you all the
code that is there in the repo.
So this is how you download any public
repo by using just git clone command.
Git clone and the URL of the repository.