In the previous section, we learned how
to create a repository on our computer,
but that repository right now
exists only on our local machine.
Now, what we want is
to have that repository
on the remote server,
which is on the GitHub.
In order to do that, we
need to start with the GitHub.
We need to create a new
repository on the GitHub.
The second step is that once
you have created the repository,
it will give you a URL
for the remote repository.
Next, you need to tell Git
that what is the remote URL.
So you need to add the
remote using command git remote,
add the name of the remote
and the URL which you have
been provided when you
created the repository.
Once you add the remote, the third step
is to push your branch to the remote,
and that's it. You will have your
project hosted on the remote server.
Let's see how this looks in practice.
Let's go back to our
project, which is Git course.
So now I want to, this is my project.
It has file one and gitignore
and a bunch of more folders.
Now I want to push
this to my remote server.
In order to do that, first I
will go to github.com and here
you can click on repositories
and on the right hand side,
click on new, new repository.
There's also a shortcut that you can use
if you want to create a new repository.
You can simply do depot.new,
and you will be landed to
this Create New Repository page.
So now let's call it GetVideoCourse.
Add description. This
is a Git video course.
Now there are two options here. One is
the public and another one is private.
The public repositories are the
repositories which are visible to everyone.
So basically anybody can
view this repository and they
can go to your GitHub
profile and see what you have.
If you want to make it private, you
can go with the private. In that case,
only you will have
access to the repository
and nobody else would be able to view it.
For now, I'm good with the public
ones, so I'll just keep it as public.
There is also an option
to add a README file.
I will just leave it for now.
Gitignore, there's also
a template which you can
choose from here in
the Gitignore template,
but we have already added a
Gitignore file, so I will not choose any,
but you can basically
select any template as well,
and it will generate a template for you,
similar to the one which we
saw in the previous section.
Now just hit create repository.
So now what we want to do is that we
already have a repository on our local machine.
So we are in this, in this case,
like we have a repository
on our local and we want to
push the existing
repository to the GitHub server.
So first we need to, we have created the
repository. Now we want to add remote,
so I will just copy this command.
So this is my, this is the
URL of my remote server.
This is where my repository
will exist on the remote server.
So I will just copy this command, and
here I will simply type git remote add,
This is the name, this is an alias,
because for the URL, it is a quite long URL,
so I will tell Git to
use origin as the name
whenever I want to read
and write to the URL.
You can basically name it anything, you
can also name it as whatever you want,
your own name, or just a random name,
but make sure that you will have to use
it again, and mostly in Git, we use origin.
So once we have added the remote,
now you can verify if the remote has
been added with command git remote minus v,
and it says that, okay,
your remote name is origin,
which you can use for pushing to the
repo and also reading from the repo.
Now if I want to push it,
so this is a push command.
It is used to push your
changes to the remote server.
Let's run git push.
Okay, now we are getting the
error, fail to push some revs to this.
Let's verify if our
remote is set correctly.
I think it is.
Okay, we have it set.
So why we are getting this error is
basically because we don't have any commits.
So right now, if I do grid
status, I have not made any commit,
so if you are trying to
push an empty commit,
it's possible that you
will get this error,
fail to push some riffs
because nothing exists.
So what I'm going to do is
that we can make a commit.
Don't worry about the syntax.
Get into these commands in detail
as we progress through the code.
So I need to first add the files and
make a commit using a git commit command.
So now I have made a
commit, and now if I do git push,
You can see the local repository is pushed
to this remote repository that we created.
So we can go and check in our GitHub
that if we have the files already.
I will just refresh this one,
and you can see we have
gitignore and file1.txt already.
Now, in our local, we had more files.
So you see in this local repo, we
also have coverage and node modules,
but we did not see it in our remote.
And that is because we added
these files in the gitignore.
So if you have a specified git that
these are the files I don't want to track,
I don't want it to be a part of
git, then when you are pushing,
git doesn't care about
pushing these folders and files.
So now you know how to push your local
repository to your remote repository.
The next thing I also want to talk
about is the remote name. For now,
what we have done is that we have
kept the remote name as origin.
You must have noticed when
I do git remote minus v,
it shows origin with the remote URL, but
you can also rename it to anything else,
and for that, you can use git
remote rename, the old remote name,
and then your new remote name.
Let's try it out.
Now, if I want to check the remote
name, I can do git remote minus v.
And right now, it is origin,
and this is the remote repo URL,
and we are calling it origin.
Now, just to remind you
that origin is just an alias.
You can name it anything.
So we'll do git remote.
Rename.
Instead of origin, I want
to use, let's say, base.
So first we need to type the origin,
the old name, and then the new name,
which I'm calling it base. And
now let's verify remote minus V,
and it's changed to base.
So now if we do, then you can do
git push, not origin, but base.
Now, instead of
pushing your existing repo,
you can also start directly with
the GitHub, create a repo, clone it,
and then start to working on it.
So let's see how that looks.
Let's say I did not start with my
repository on my local machine,
but instead I can just go to repo.new.
Okay, I have typo in my URL, repo.new.
Let's create another repo.
Git repo demo.
Demo for Git repository.
Let's create this repo.
And now instead of using
Pushing an existing repository.
Now I don't have this repo
at all on my local machine.
So what I can do is I will just copy it,
copy the URL and clone the
repository into my computer.
So let's go back to our folder and
here do git clone and write the URL.
Now let's move to this repo with CD.
So right now, it's an empty
repository. I'm trying to open it in my VS Code.
There's nothing in it,
but it's a Git repository.
So now you can just start to
add files like I did, file1.txt.
This is my Git repo.
Now, if you do git status, then
it also shows you that, okay,
you have this file which you have created.
So we can do the same
thing as we did before.
We added a file, git add all,
and then we will commit it.
First repo, and then git push.
Let's verify.
So we have the file1.txt in our remote
repo. So here, the commit that we did,
it is the repo, the changes
are pushed to the remote server.
Let's recap again.
So we saw there were two ways.
So first thing what we did was that
we pushed an existing repo to GitHub.
So we started with our local
computer. We created a project.
And then we pushed the
files to the remote server.
So this is how I usually start
whenever I want to create a new project.
I often start with the local
machine. I just create it on my computer,
initialize it as a Git repository,
and then push it to the remote server.
Another way which we saw was that
you start with the GitHub. You start,
create a Git repo with repo.new, And
then you copy that URL from the GitHub,
clone the repo in your local
machine, and push your changes.
So it depends on you, however you prefer.
You can start from the local
machine and then push it to GitHub,
or you can clone from the
GitHub and start to work on it.