Just to recap what we
learned in this section,
the first thing we talked
about was version control.
So we talked about
what is version control.
Git is an open source
version control system,
which gives us ability
to track changes within
the same file without
creating multiple files.
Also, it allows us to
collaborate with other people.
Then we also talked about what is GitHub.
In GitHub, we saw that Git and
GitHub both are two separate things.
Git is a version control software,
whereas GitHub is a hosting
platform where you can host your
Git repositories so that
you can work with your peers.
Then we talked about Git
terminologies. We talked about three terminologies.
The first one we talked
about was Git repository.
We saw that repository is nothing but
a project with .git folder inside it.
And that .git folder does
all the tracking for you.
Next we talked about was remote,
and we saw that the project on our
local machine has to be hosted on
the remote server if we want to
work together with our teammates.
So that is a remote
server, which we call remote.
Third we talked about is origin.
And we saw that whenever we host our
project on GitHub, it provides us with a URL,
which is a remote URL of the repository.
Because the URL is long, we
provide it an alias, origin,
because that is handy to use.
Third we talked about was
the setup and configurations.
We learned how to install
Git on our local machine.
We saw the setups for
Mac, Linux, and Windows.
After the setup, we saw
how we can configure Git.
There are mainly two things that we
need to add to the Git config file.
One is your name, another
one is your email address.
Make sure the email address that
you are adding in the configuration
is same as the one you have
registered with on your GitHub profile.
Next, we talked about
creating and cloning repositories.
We saw how we can create our
repository starting on our local machine.
We also saw that how we
can download any public
repository with the git clone command.
And finally, we talked
about how to push our existing
repository on our local
machine to the GitHub server.
We saw two ways that we can,
whenever we are starting with the project,
we can either start with our local
computer, start a project there,
and then push it to GitHub server.
Alternatively, you can
also start with the GitHub.
You can create a repo there. You
can use repo.new as a shortcut.
And create your repository. Once
you have the link to your repository,
you can clone it to your
computer and start to make changes.
Time to move to the exercise now. So part
one of this exercise is create a project.
You can name your project
anything, whatever you like.
And create a file, learninggit.txt in it.
You can add any content in that text file.
Commit the file and push
the project on the GitHub.
Part two of this exercise is that
try to change the name of the origin.
You can change it to base.
Change the file and then push
it to your remote server again.
Change the remote name
back to origin and verify
if the remote is changed
back to original or not.
You can do it with git
remote hyphen b command.
You can check if the
origin is set correctly.