So in Git, there are four
areas where your code lives.
The first one is your
local working directory.
This is the place where you
make changes to your files.
So this is your coding editor, like
VS Code or whichever you are using.
Second place is the staging area.
This is a special area where
you keep your finalized changes.
So you basically tell Git
that these are the finalized
changes which are ready to be committed.
Third area is local repository.
So this is the place
in your local computer.
This is your local .git
folder in your project.
And the last one is the remote repository.
So this is the .git folder in the
remote server, which is the GitHub.
So talking about how
the workflow looks like.
So whenever you are
starting with any project,
you would basically
cloning a remote repository.
You would use the git clone command,
and that will download that
repository to your local machine.
After that, you will start to
make changes in your files.
And once you are working on it,
making changes, and you want to commit it,
you would be doing git add.
Add them to the staging areas, all the
changes which you have made to the files.
And then you would be
committing it to your local repository.
So all the changes in the staging area
will go to the local repository after commit.
You will run git commit command,
and it will commit the
changes to the local repository.
But right now, it's only
on your local machine.
In order to push it, push
your changes to the remote,
you will use the kit push command.
Sometimes you also need to
integrate your teammates work.
Let's say your teammate
is also working on the
same project and he or
she has some changes.
Now you also want to
integrate his or her changes.
So you can use get pull
command and that will bring
all the changes which
are made to the repository
by your peers or your
coworkers that will be
integrated to your
local working directory.
Instead of pull, you can
also use git fetch command.
It is a little bit
different than git pull command.
We will talk about it in
the later section as well.
But basically, if you are using git fetch,
what git fetch will do is
that it will copy the .git
folder from remote repo
to your local repository.
But the changes will not
come to your working directory.
Which means that Git will be
aware that there are some changes,
but if you want to integrate
it to your working directory,
you need to run git merge command.
So git pull is a shortcut. It's like git
pull is equal to git fetch plus git merge.
Let's practice this
workflow and see how this looks.
So we already have a repository like Git
Video Course. I'm just going to clone it.
So just copy it and let's say git clone.
Now I've cloned the repository.
I can go to get video course folder.
And open it in my coding editor.
So there are already some files here.
I can just change some
text in the file one.
So this is my...
Changes for git workflow.
Let's create another
file as well, file2.txt.
Practice git workflow.
Now, if you want to see what
all changes you have made,
you can also run the status command,
and you can see the git
tells you that you have one file
which is modified and another file
which is a new file, which is file two.
We can also see the changes
from the Visual Studio Code.
So if you just Go to
the source control. Yeah.
So in the source control tab, just
click on the source control. And here,
if you just click on any of the
file, it will show you your changes.
So these are the changes which I made,
and these were the changes
which were already in the remote.
And in the file too, we
have all new changes.
So it tells you that
you have added this file.
So the green ones are the
changes which you added and the red
ones are the changes which
were already there from the,
which are coming from the remote.
Okay. So now we have made the changes.
Now we can use git add command.
And what git add command does is that it
adds your changes to the staging area.
Now you can add all the
files to the staging area,
but you can also select some
files for the staging area.
So let's say I only want to add
file1.txt in the staging area.
So I can do git add and file1.txt,
and that will only add my
file1.txt into the staging area.
So this means that when I do git
commit, only file1.txt will be committed.
The file2.ext will not be
committed because it is not staged.
So all the changes that you want
to commit to your local repository,
you first need to add
them to the staging area.
This staging area is really helpful. For
example, you're working on a big feature,
you made a lot of changes, but you want
to break those changes in smaller commits.
So it's possible that you
say that only a certain number
of changes are the changes
for the particular commit.
The rest of the changes are maybe
some drafts or they are not finalized.
So this staging area is really helpful
when you are working with a lot of files.
So let's now commit it. For
committing, we can use git commit minus m.
Minus m is for the message, and
here we can write staging area demo.
Now we have committed, and
if we run git status command,
so you can see that this file was not
sent to your commit. Now if I do git push,
it will push the changes
to the remote repository,
but it will not include the file 2.txt.
Now next thing is, let's push our changes.
Let's also push the
another file. So get status,
right now we have file
two, which is not added.
So let's also add it.
You can also add multiple files
together, and if you want to add all the files,
then you can use simply dot.
So if I had like more files,
file 3, 4, 5, if I did git add dot,
it will add all the
files to the staging area.
So let's add that and also do git commit.
Minus M, more changes.
And now I have two commits, so I
will just push these changes. Okay.
Now we can check.
On our remote repository, so the file
one, these are my changes from Git workflow,
so I already made changes to the
files which are reflecting here,
and then I also changed
file to practice Git workflow.
So we have the changes which are
pushed to the remote repository.
Now let's say your teammate made
some changes to this repository.
So let's create a file here.
Let's call it file3.txt.
More changes into the repository.
Yeah, just committed.
Now there are changes in this
repository, but in the local repository,
the file three does not exist.
So let's go back to our local repository.
And right now, you can see in the git
status, Yeah, there is nothing to commit.
We have committed all our changes, but
right now there is no, uh, file three.
Right. But on our remote,
there is file three as well.
So we want to
integrate the remote changes.
So for that, we can do get pull.
And now we have file three.
So this is how you will integrate your
teammates work in your local computer.
So all the new changes which
are in the remote repository,
you can integrate it to your local
repository by using git pull command.
Let's see what would have
happened if I used git fetch.
Let's add a new file,
file4.txt, testing git fetch.
So now instead of git
pull, I will use git fetch.
So here I do git fetch.
Now, I used git fetch, but
there is no file four here.
So this file four was not created in my
local repository, but if you do git status,
it says that your branch is
behind the origin main by one commit.
Origin main is the remote repo,
so you are behind it
because there is one commit
additional which includes the file for,
but my local repository does
not know anything about it.
So if we want to integrate those
changes, now we can do git merge.
If we do git merge, we
will get the same file for.
So we have integrated these
changes to our local repository.
Git pull is a
shortcut. If you do git pull,
you directly pull the changes
from the remote to your local.
If you use git fetch, then
you can review those changes.
If you want to merge it
to your local repository,
you need to additionally
use git merge command.