We are going to practice more on
adding and committing the files.
So what we are going to do in this
section is basically create a new repository.
Then we'll create new files,
change some existing files,
and add files to the staging area. And
finally, we make commit to the repository.
I would be using Visual Studio
Code, so use any text editor you want.
So let's practice.
Let's start with creating a
directory. Let's say git commit demo.
Let's move to this git commit demo
and open it in the coding editor.
Okay, right now it's an empty
project. It's not a git repository.
And how do we know
it's not a git repository
is because if I do ls,
there's nothing in it.
In order to make it a Git
repository, we need to do git init.
Now, one thing I want you to
notice here is that as I did get in it,
there is some message
in the yellow that using
master as the name of the initial branch,
this default branch
name is subject to change.
So basically, by default, Git has
initialized the branch as master.
And if you do git status, it will
tell you that you are on branch master.
However, on GitHub, main is
used as the default branch,
so it will often ask you to
change the master branch name to main.
It depends on project to project.
Some projects use trunk, some projects
use develop, some projects use master.
So it's really based on the project.
We would be working mainly with the main.
So I will rename it to main.
There is another way
which you can also change
your default branch
name from master to main.
So it says that if you want to
change your default branch name,
you can simply add it to the config.
So that the next time
when you do git init,
it will initialize it
as main and not master.
So let's see what happens if I run this.
So git config Just copy it again.
Git config in a default
branch, and here, if I
want to change it to
main, I will type main.
If you want to change it to trunk, you
can type here trunk, but let's stick to main.
So now it has changed the
default branch name to main,
but this is for the next time. So
next time, whenever you do git init,
it will change it to, it will
initialize it with main, but for now,
it has already initialized with master.
So one thing we can do is in order to
change this branch, we can run a command.
So Git already tells us that you can
run this command, git branch minus m,
and it will change the
default branch name.
So let's run this command, git branch
minus m, and I want to change it to main,
so I will just type main, and
now, now if I do git status,
it tells you on branch
main, there are no commits yet.
But yeah, the branch name is main.
How else you can tell that
you have... This is a Git repo.
It's also... You can check
ls-a, and there is a .git folder,
so it's a Git repository, and
also Git status is working,
so you know that the
depository has been...
Initialize properly.
Now we already have the Git
repository. Let's add some more files.
Let's add file1.txt.
This is commit demo1.
Demo file 1.
Let's add two more files.
File 2.txt, file 3.txt, and
I will just... This is...
Commit demo file 2.
Let's copy, and in the file 3,
so I've created three new files.
Now if I do git status, it is
showing me three untracked files.
Now, in order to commit it, I first
need to add them to my staging area.
So let's add git add.
Let's say I just want to
add file one and file two.
So just copy the name
file one and file two.
If I...
Add it here.
So now if we check git status.
So in the git status, we have
two files in the staging area.
So these are changes to be committed.
If you also want to add
file 3, do git add file3.txt.
And now if we do git status, we have
three files which are staged to be committed.
In order to commit it, we
need to run the commit command,
which is git commit minus m.
Commit demo, and yeah.
So now the files, now the commit
is there, so we have made a commit.
Here, let's see how we
can do these things,
how we can commit and add files
using VS Code graphical user interface.
So let's say I want to
change some files. So let's say,
let's change the text of file1.ext.
This is using VS code.
So now in this source control
tab, just click on source control,
and this will tell you that these
are the changes. If you click on it,
you will see what changes are there.
And if you need to add it to the
staging area, just click on plus icon.
This will add the changes into the
staged area. It's very simple using VS code.
So you can also Instead of command line,
you can use Visual Studio Code interface.
In order to unstage, you can
also use the minus sign here,
so it will unstage the changes.
Let me also make some more changes
using VS Code, and here also using VS Code.
Let's go to the source control tab again.
And you can also add
all the changes together,
like using this plus icon in front of
the changes. So if you click on plus,
it says stage all changes.
So if you click on plus, this
will stage all the changes.
If you want to verify, you
can verify using its status,
and all the changes are
there to be committed.
In order to unstage, unstage all
changes, click on Minus, and then Get Status.
The changes are unstaged.
Let's add all of them and
make a commit using VS Code.
So first, stage all the changes.
Commit using VS code.
So now it's, just click
on commit and that's done.
Now if I do get status, yeah.
We can see if the, Commit is made
or not. So we have the commit here.
So we will talk about git log command in
the next section only. So with git log,
you can view your commit.
So we can see all the
commits that we made are here.
So this is how you can Make add
changes to your staging area, make a commit,
and also do the same using VS
Code graphical user interface.