Before we jump into using
git fetch and git pull,
let's quickly see what git log command is.
So this command basically
tells you the history of
all the commits you have
made to the repository.
The history of commits include
hash, messages, and metadata.
We will be practicing three commands,
git log, git log hyphen hyphen author,
and git log hyphen hyphen one line.
Let's see what these commands look like.
So going back to our
previous project, git commit demo,
we already saw the git log command.
Let's recap again. So if we do git log,
it displays the
history of all the commits.
And in the commits, you can
see there is this long hash.
So this is your hash,
which is used basically to
if you want to
identify a particular commit.
And then you have author who made
the commit and the commit message.
And if you have some metadata,
like commit footers or dates,
anything that is also
displayed in the Git log.
Now, if you want to filter
out the commits using author,
then you can do git log hyphen hyphen
author, and just type the name of the author.
So I wrote Ashima, and I can
see all the commits by Ashima.
If you just search by
author, let's say Pete,
it did not show any commits
because Pete did not make any commit.
Now, if you must have noticed in
the git log, it is like really long.
Sometimes what we only want to see
is like a concise version of it.
We only are concerned about
the author and maybe the hash.
So you can use git log
hyphen hyphen one line.
And this is much more cleaner. You can
view more commits and you can see the hash.
It doesn't show you the author, sorry,
but it shows you the commit
message and the commit hash.
So that was it about Git log command.