We have already seen these
commands in the previous section,
but let's dive deeper into
it. So what is git pull doing?
So whenever we want to
integrate remote repository
changes to the working
directory, we use git pull.
Just to recap, your working
directory is where you are making changes.
So this is your coding
editor. This is your VS code.
Now on the GitHub repository,
if there are more changes and you want
to integrate it to your local computer,
then you will do Git pull and it will
bring the changes to your working directory.
Another command is git fetch.
What git fetch does is that it only
copies the .git folder to your local repository,
which means that now git
knows that there are changes,
but the changes are not made
to your working directory.
It doesn't come into your VS code.
So git fetch will download the
changes from GitHub remote repository,
but you will not see those
changes in your working directory.
Fetch will allow you to
review the changes before
you actually merge it in
your working directory.
Let's practice git fetch and git pull.
Let's go to our git
video course repository.
CD, git.
CD get video course.
Let's open it in our editor and
let's change some text in the file one.
These are my changes for
get fetch and get pull.
Let's delete some files this time.
Yeah, I think one and two would be
good. Let's delete file three as well.
So practice git pull and git fetch.
Yeah, let's git add, and then git
commit, fetch and pull demo, and let's push.
In this repository git video course,
let's make some changes
directly into this repo.
So let's say, let's add a
file. Let's refresh, yeah.
So now we don't have file
three and file four, but let's,
let's make the changes in file one.
Added from remote.
So let's commit this.
I updated file1.ext.
Now if I do git pull, so
right now in the file1,
I have these other changes
for git fetch and git pull.
But now if I do git pull, it
will change the text of file1.
And because it merged the
changes from the remote to the local.
Now let's see what
happens when we do git fetch.
Let's make another commit.
Let's change file to text this time.
Remote changed file to text.
Let's commit the changes.
And this time, I'm going to do
git fetch instead of git pull.
I'll git fetch.
So git fetch brought the changes, but
the text of file two, it's still the same.
Practice git pull and git fetch.
So what...
From if I do git status, it tells me
that you are behind because there is one
change which is in the remote, but
it is not in your working directory.
So what git fetch did was
that it copied the .git folder
so that my git is aware
that there are changes,
but the changes are not
merged in my working directory.
What is the benefit of git
fetch is that sometimes you want to
review what changes are there
before you want to merge it.
Basically you want to know
what were the changes, right?
So what we can do is
we can check git diff.
Main and origin main.
Origin main is your
remote repository main branch.
And this is my local branch.
So I want to know what
is the difference between
the main and the remote main branch.
So now it says that file
to text has been changed.
So From the remote, it's
remote change the file to text,
but you have practice
get pull and get fetch.
So with the green, it tells you
that which are the incoming changes,
like which are the changes
that were coming from the remote.
And the red ones are the changes which
you have made in your local repository,
like which are the changes which
currently exist in your local repository.
So these are the new changes
which are added into the remote.
Now, if you are okay with these
changes and you want to include it,
so you can do git merge, and
you will have the changes here.
Sorry, file to remote
change, file to text.
So that is the basic difference
between git pull and git fetch.
Git pull will pull the changes
directly to your working directory.
Git fetch will only copy the .git
folder, and once you hit git merge,
then you will be seeing those
changes in your local repository.