In Git, we are basically
dealing with a lot of commands,
and some of these
commands are really long.
So what we can do is that
we can set up aliases for
those long commands so
that it's easy for us to use.
Let's see how we can do it.
The first way I'm going to
show you is using the git config.
So we would be adding aliases for
the commands in the git config.
Let's see how to do this.
So let's open our Code.getconfig.
Let's open our config
file. And here I want to,
there are already some aliases
existing. Okay, so basically,
you can add s for status.
Let's say I want to add
PP for push, or just P
for push, or actually pull.
So let's say P for pull,
S for status, L for log.
So instead of using
now the whole commands,
I can use this abbreviations like aliases.
So if I just go, and here I
use, instead of git status,
so this tells me the
status, but I can use git s,
and that will execute the same command.
If I want to do the log, then I can do
git l, and this will tell me the log.
So this is git log hyphen hyphen one line.
So we have...
Change this command, created alias,
and it's simply we can write git l.
Similar for the git add, you can do git a,
and it will nothing to add
because we don't have any changes here.
And for commit, you can also do git add.
CI, I have added, you can create any
alias, like you can also do just C, so get C.
This is also good, but there is
another way, which I'm going to show you.
And that is more convenient
because here we are still
writing git and then we
are writing the commands.
So another way to do it
is by setting up those
aliases in your shell, like .zrc file.
If you're using bash, then you
add these aliases in your bash rc.
So just copy these aliases, alias GST,
like I've created GST for Git status,
which means that whenever I will use
GST, it will execute Git status command.
Then for Git clone, I can
use GCL, GA for Git add.
You can add a lot many
aliases as you want.
There are a lot more
available on the internet,
but these are the basic
ones which I use a lot.
So you can just copy it and
add it to your ZSHRC file.
I will show you how to do it in your
ZSHRC. So let's see how to do this.
So first, you need to
open your ZSHRC file.
If you are working with bash
shell, then you will have bash rc.
So let's open ZSHRC.
So I'm using this theme, power level 9K.
So this theme already
comes with those aliases.
So even though I have not added any of
those aliases, it still works for me.
But you can add your
own, like here, alias, GST.
And git status.
Let's try. So we have aliases
set. You can add as much as one.
More for git add, git add
all, or git commit as well.
So here, let's try it
out, and let's run GST,
and now it executes
the git status command.
It's really helpful because as you work
with a lot of commands like git checkout,
there will be a lot more commands that
will be coming in the next sections.
If you create aliases, it's
really fast to work with git.
For example, if I have to make any
commit, I can just do gc-m and my commit message.
So right now, there is no file, no
changes, so there is nothing to be committed,
but if you just do any
change, let's change one file.
This is changed.
Let's add one more file,
file3.txt, aliases demo.
So now if I need to do all this, all the
steps like adding, committing, pushing,
I can do it with the aliases really fast.
Like first I can do GAA,
which is for git add all.
This is something which I have
created for adding all files. Of course,
you can write git add dot.
But I just took it, add all, GST, all
files are added, and then I have to commit,
then GC minus M, area says demo.
And if I want to check if this
is committed or not, I do glg,
and this tells me that you have a
commit already made to the local repo.
So these are the two ways
you can create Git aliases.
You can either
configure it in your Git config
file, or you can go with
the ZSHRC, add your...
Aliases in the ZSH-RC and work with that.
So both are good. I prefer the
ZSH-RC. You can use whichever you prefer.