Let's recap what we learned in this
lesson. So we talked about Git workflow,
in which we saw that your code lives in
four areas throughout the Git workflow,
which is your local directory, your
staging area, your local repository,
and your remote repository.
Second, we talked about adding and
committing files to get repository.
We also saw how to do
commit and adding files
using VS code graphical user interface.
Then we saw some more git commands,
which is git log to check
the history of commits.
We also saw git fetch and git pull.
We also checked what is the
difference between git pull and git fetch.
Then finally, we saw how
we can create Git aliases,
which can help us running
those commands faster. Basically,
you can configure it in your Git config,
or you can also add it to your ZSH
RC and use aliases for the commands.
Moving on to the exercise.
So part one is practice all the
commands that we learned in this lesson.
So try git status, git add, git log,
git commit, git fetch, and git pull.
Also, try it using VS Code.
Try all the commands.
Try to see how you can
use leverage VS Code to
run all these things.
Part two is add
aliases for these commands.
I would highly encourage
you to add the aliases and
use aliases because when
you are working every day,
the aliases are really helpful.
Thank you and see you in the next lesson.