Let's dive deeper into commits.
So what is a commit?
Commit is basically the
snapshot of the project taken by Git.
So whenever you're working on a project,
you are making any changes to the files,
you will add them to the staging
area. And when you say Git commit,
what Git does is that it
will take snapshot of the exact
state of the project and put
it to your local repository.
Snapshots are always
committed to your local repository.
If you want your commits to be
pushed to the remote repository,
then you have to use git push command.
Now, how can we create perfect commits?
Or I would say better commits.
So rule number one is
creating granular commits.
Let's say you were working
on a bunch of files. Now,
one way is that you add
everything inside a single commit,
but that is not good because in case there
is any bug or you need
to make any changes,
you will have to revert all the changes.
So instead, what you can do is
that you can create smaller commits.
Smaller commits has a bunch of benefits.
For example, it's easier
to review the changes.
Also, if there is any mistake
or any bug in one of the commit,
it's easy to roll back that commit
without changing the rest of the commits.
So creating granular commits is better
than creating a single large commit.
Now, when I say creating granular commits,
I don't mean that you create a
single commit for each file,
but let's say you are working on
a big feature like user login.
And now user login has a login
screen. It has authentication.
It has some backend API integrations.
So instead of doing all
the work in a single commit,
what you can do is that you can break
down the functionality into multiple commits,
like you can have UI changes in one
commit, testing changes in another commit,
and then backend
integrations in a separate commit.
You can leverage the staging area
for creating those smaller commits.
So basically, if you
have made all the changes,
but you want to break it
down into three commits,
so you can start by adding the commits
into the staging area for only that commit.
So you can push only your
stage changes into one commit,
and then add more to your staging
area and add it to the second commit.
Another important thing
in creating good commits
is writing a valuable commit message.
So commit message is
really important because this
gives you basically idea
about what the commit is.
And if your teammates are
also reviewing the commits,
it's easier for them to
understand what this commit is about.
So the good commit
message should have a brief and
concise subject line that
summarizes the changes.
It can have a descriptive message body
that explain most of the important facts.
And what you can also do is
leverage conventional commits.
I will talk more about
conventional commits in the later sections.