Now we know how to make a commit, but
let's see how we can amend a commit.
So we can basically, we
are going to do two things.
We are going to be amending a
commit message, and second,
we are going to be amending a
file in the existing commit.
Let's see how that looks.
Let's go back to our Git
video course repository.
So in the file one, I
will change the text.
So it is amending commits demo one.
Let's make this commit, git add all,
and git commit, amend commit, demo one.
Now let's say I want to amend this
commit message. So first of all,
I can check what the commit
message is by checking into git log.
So this is my commit message
for amend commit demo one.
Let's say I want to change this
commit message to something else.
So I can use this command, git commit,
hyphen hyphen amend, and then minus m,
and this is new commit message.
Now let's check git log.
And the commit message has been changed.
Now let's say I wanted to make another
change in the same commit, but I forgot.
Like, let's say I also wanted to
change this file, amend demo two.
I want to add file
two, but I want it to be
a part of this new commit message commit.
So how can I add this
file into the same commit?
I can do git, first of all, git add.
So we can do git commit, hyphen
hyphen amend, hyphen hyphen no edit.
We don't need to specify
any commit message because
we are adding this file
into the existing commit.
So now if you do git log,
And you check this commit.
So basically, it has now
two files instead of one.
And it says two files changed.