So we already talked about
conventional commits. Let's see what they are.
Conventional commits
specification provides an easy
set of rules for writing
commit messages properly.
So what it says is that if you
have to write a commit message,
you will define what is the
type of the commit message.
Then you will define the
scope and description.
You also can define
optional body and footer.
So if you're using conventional
commit, the type is the type of commit.
So there are four or five types
which you can use. Like, for example,
for a bug fix, it can be a fix.
For a feature, the type can be feet.
There are other types, like core,
if you are updating any
library or there is some cleanup.
Then you have refactor, if
there are any refactors.
For the test, you can mention it as test.
For the CSS or any other style
changes, you can mention it as styles.
For the documents, you can specify docs.
So this clearly tells that what
is the type of commit message.
In order to highlight some commits
that there can be some commits which
are really important or which
you want to pay more attention to.
So you can use exclamation sign,
which tells that this is a breaking
change and it needs more attention.
So these are just some
types which you can use.
Fix, colon, resolve issue with user
registration, then feature, feat, colon,
add user authentication feature.
For refactor, you have refactor,
extract validation, for core,
core, clean up unused dependencies.
So these are some of the
examples how your commit messages
will look if you are
using conventional commits.
Next we also talked about was scope.
What is a scope in conventional commit?
So you basically define a
scope in your parenthesis.
So this tells that what
this feature is about.
For example, in this
case, it's like language,
and I've specified this
feature is related to language.
So it says add Polish language.
But let's say you are working on,
again, like authentication or user login.
So your feature can be
related to user login.
So in that case, all the commits
which are related to user login,
you can specify feed user login.
Often what we also do is that we, in
the scope, we specify the epic name.
So if you're working with Jira, you are
familiar with epics, then in the epic,
we usually specify the epic. Like,
for example, if this is related to...
Reporting. So I would add like
feature reporting and the message.
So this gives a very good idea
about what this feature is about.
And if you are looking for a particular
commit, it's easy to find in the history.
For drawing the attention,
how you would use exclamation sign is
along with the type. So like feature,
exclamation, and then you
provide your commit message.
You can also specify with
breaking change text and colon
and add what is the
breaking change in this commit.
So basically you specify that
this is an important commit,
but why this is important
because this has this breaking change.
There are also commit
messages with body and footer,
and you will see it a lot many
times in the design system repos.
So in design systems, they usually
add a lot of, in a single commit,
they add a lot of body,
what are the changes in
that particular commit,
and also the footers.
So how this looks is that you...
Add a proper description, but then you
add more what are the changes. For example,
if you are building a model component,
then you would add like
what all changes it has
related to model,
dialogues, all those things.
And then in the footer, you can
specify like co-authored by this person,
this closes this, this resolve this
issue number, so you can specify that.
One thing to note here
is that when you are
drafting commit
messages, use present tense.
For example, if you are
implementing user authentication,
your conventional commit
message should be like implement user
authentication and not
implemented user authentication.
I've also specified a link
of conventional commits,
so there are more rules
which you can Look into,
there are extended more things you
can do with it. It's a really nice way.
And if you are not using
it in your company project,
it's a very good way to
introduce it as it helps a lot.
Then you are reviewing the comments.
Let's go back to our
Git video course repo.
Here, let's create a new
file. Let's say login.js.
So I will just create a
function, console.log.
Let's say I also create a login.html.
Let's say login screen.
So now I want to, so these two
files are related to my login feature.
So when I commit, I can do is git add all,
but I will also do is git commit
minus m, and how I will specify this,
because this is a feature, so I will
do feed, and I will add the scope,
which is this feature, this is login,
And then I will specify
or implement user login.
Implement user login.
Sometimes what we also do is that we
specify the task ID or the Jira ID, like T123.
So this is also really helpful.
If you want to go back to the
task and see what the task is,
you specify in your commit message.
So now you can commit it
with the proper commit message.
In case there was a bug, I wanted to
fix it. So let's say I fix the bug.
Now if I make any change,
and I want to make a commit,
I will do git commit minus
m, and instead of now feed,
because this is a bug
fix, so I will do fix.
I will also provide the
scope, what this fix is about.
Sorry, which feature this fix is
for. So it's for the login feature,
and here I will add fix user login.
There are also conventions
about the casing. In some projects,
I have seen that using always small
case, but there's no hard and fast rule.
You can check more in the conventional
commits, and here you specify the ID.
So this was everything
about conventional commits,
how to write proper commit messages.