Let's quickly see what
git diff command is.
So this command tells you
the differences between the
current version of the
files and your last commit.
Let's see how this looks like.
So let's say I change
here login functionality.
Now if I want to see what is the
difference, then I can do git diff,
and this will tell me what
is the difference between
my current changes from the last commit.
So in the last commit, it was bug,
but I have added login functionality.
So it will tell with the green
that you have made this change,
but your previous commit had bug.
There is another way. So
I don't use diff command
a lot because I prefer to
use Visual Studio Code.
So if you go to the source control
again, and then just click on the file,
and this will tell you that
this was the previous change,
and this is the new
change which you have added.
But feel free to use git diff command.
So it only compares with the last commit,
but you can also compare
with the Previous, more
previous commits, let's
say, let's see git log.
Let's say I want to
check with this commit,
what is the difference between my
current version and the second last commit.
So I will do git diff the commit
hash, And it says that commit had login,
but your current version
has login functionality.
So with the diff command, you can
basically compare your changes with any commit.
So that was it about get diff command.