Let's recap what we
learned in this lesson.
So we learned how to
create perfect commits.
We saw the first rule is
to create granular commits,
and the second is to write
commit messages properly.
We talked about conventional commits,
how we can write better commit
messages using conventional commits.
We also talked about amending commits.
We saw that we can amend commit message,
and also we can add files
into the same commit if we have
forgotten to add any file
in a particular commit.
Then we also talked about git diff
command, that with git diff command,
we can compare our
changes with the latest commit,
but also we can use
the git diff command to
compare our current
changes with any commit.
Coming to the exercise,
I want you to practice
making commit and not
just making a commit,
but also trying to write commit
messages using conventional commits.
So practice with conventional commits,
practice different types
of conventional commits.
Second thing I want you to try is amend a
commit using conventional commit message.
Change the commit message.
And third, I want you to create a new
file and add it to the same commit.