Welcome to lesson four, Undoing Changes.
In this lesson, we will explore
the essential commands in Git that
help you reverse or modify
changes in your project history.
These are invaluable when
you need to fix mistakes.
We will begin by learning how
to use git checkout command
to switch between
branches and restore files,
followed by understanding git restore
command to revert working directory changes.
Then we'll dive into Git reset
to undo commits. And finally,
we'll explore Git revert,
a command used to undo changes
safely in a collaborative environment.
And to check your understanding,
we'll run through an exercise.
That's the roadmap for this
lesson. Let's get started.