Git checkout is a superpower command.
It can be used to do multiple things.
The first thing which you can do with
checkout command is switch branches.
So you can run git checkout and the
branch name where you want to move to.
Second thing which you
can do with the checkout
command is undo the changes in your file.
You need to do git checkout and the file
which you want to undo the changes in.
Third, which you can do with the git
checkout is moving to a commit or tag.
So you can do git
checkout and have a commit hash,
and it will move you to that commit.
Let's see how we can use checkout command.
Let's go to our file one, and I'm on
the same repository Git video course.
I will change this text to checkout demo.
Now if I do git status, it tells me
that you have modified file1.txt.
Let's run git diff.
Git diff tells me that
these were the changes before.
This is changes added from remote.
And now I have changed
the text to checkout demo.
Now, if I want to go back to my previous
changes, the one which I had committed,
I can use git checkout command.
I can do git checkout and the file.
So let's copy this file name because I
want to restore the changes of file1.txt.
And now you can see the changes are back.
You can also do the same from the
VS Code graphical user interface.
So let's make the changes again.
Let's say I've made
checkout demo changes again.
And now go to the source control tab.
In the VS Code source control tab,
you will see discard
changes in front of the file.
There is also an option to
discard all the changes.
So if you have multiple
changes, you can discard all of them.
But let's say I just want to discard
file1.txt, then I will just click on discard,
and this will restore my
changes to the previous commit.
Now, in case you have more files
changed, like let's change file1 again.
And also change commit demo
file to checkout demo file to.
So now I have changed two files.
And if I want to discard all of those
files, then I can do git checkout dot.
This will restore all of my
files to the previous version.
Similarly, you can do with the VS
Code. Just click on Discard All Changes.
So in the changes, you
can see there is an icon.
Just click on discard all changes, and
this will discard all of your files.
The second use of checkout
command can be to switch branches.
I know we have not talked
a lot about branches yet,
but we would be talking
about it in the next lesson.
So far, let's see how we can
switch branches using checkout command.
So let me create a branch
with git branch command.
Let's call it feature checkout.
Now if I want to move to this
branch, first let's see The git status.
In git status, it says
you are on branch main,
and I want to move to
feature checkout branch.
So I can do git
checkout, feed slash checkout.
And now it says you have
switched to branch feed slash checkout.
You can verify it with the
git status command again,
and it tells you you are on this branch.
So we have seen how we can
use git checkout to restore
our files and also how to
switch between branches.
Third thing that we talked
about is moving to commits.
So let's first see the history of
our commits with git log command.
Now let's see I want to move
to the second last commit.
So first I'll copy this hash.
And then with the checkout command, I
can use git checkout and the commit hash.
We don't need the author,
so just remove this one.
So now we have moved to
the particular commit
and it says you are in
a detached head state.
This means that you
don't belong to any branch.
And if you want to make any changes,
the ideal
recommendation is that you create
a branch from this
commit using get branch.
Check out demo two.
And I also want to move to this branch.
And if I check the git log,
We are on the third last commit,
from where we cut this branch.
So all you need to remember is that
whenever you are moving to a commit,
you will be in a detached head state.
And if you want to make more
changes on top of that commit,
you need to create branches.
Don't worry if you don't understand
the branches and everything right now.
We'll get to it in the later part.