Git restore command is used to restore a
file to its previously committed state.
You can use git restore and the file name.
It is very similar to what we
did with the git checkout command.
So we were running git
checkout, file name,
and it would restore it
to its previous version.
But instead of git checkout, you can also
use git restore command to do the same.
Just make sure whenever you run git
restore command for restoring your file changes,
the changes will be permanently lost.
And this also happens
with the checkout command.
You will lose the
changes if you restore it.
We can also restore a file
to any commit in the log.
We need to tell number of
commits we need to go back to.
So you can run command
git restore hyphen hyphen
source head tilde n file underscore name.
N here refers to the number of
commits prior to head we want to go back.
We can also use git
restore to unstage the files
added to the staging area using git add.
In order to do that, just run git
restore hyphen hyphen staged file name.
Let's see all of this in practice.
So we would be practicing git restore
file name to restore the changes in the file.
Then we would be
restoring to the previous commit.
And then finally, we'll try
restoring the staged files.
So let's go back to the file1.txt again,
and let's say here I have
written git restore demo1.
Now here, you can also do git
checkout file1.txt, and this works perfect.
But instead, you can also do git
restore and the file name, file1.txt.
And now the changes are back.
One interesting thing with git
restore is that you can move
to the version of this file
to previous commits as well.
Like for example, let me
change this back and commit it.
Git add all, git commit, restore demo one.
I need to do git commit
minus m. Let's change again.
You can also use git commit hyphen
am. So this will add as well as commit.
So this is a shortcut, but it only
works if you are modifying a file.
If you have created a new
file, then it will not work.
So you will need to run
add commands separately.
But since here we are modifying an
existing file, so we can do git commit minus am.
Let's create a, Third commit as
well, so am restore demo three.
Now I want to go back to
the third last commit.
Let's say here, restore demo one,
so I want this file to be same as it
was in this commit, third last commit.
So I will just copy this hash and
say, Git restore, hyphen hyphen source,
this commit ID, and the name of the file.
Now you can see it's
restored to the third last commit.
Instead of copying the hash,
you can also use the head.
So we want to go to the third
last commit. So we can say here,
instead of commit hash,
go back three commits.
Let's first restore it back.
And now do git restore
source head 3 and file 1.txt.
Okay, we have moved further.
So we want to go two commits.
We want to go to this restore
demo one, which means from the head,
we want to go two commits before.
So I need to write here
two instead of three.
Okay, now it's restored to demo one.
So this is how you can
use the git restore command
in restoring the commits,
actually to any commit.
We can also use git
restore to unstage the changes.
So let's make two changes in the file one.
Let's change it to
unstaged, similarly unstaged.
And now I will add these
two files to my staging area.
Let's check using git status command,
and it says that you have
modified these two files,
and they have also been
added to the staging area.
Now, in order to unstage these files,
I can use git restore hyphen
hyphen staged dot, Using dot,
it will unstage all the files.
If you want to unstage a particular file,
then you need to specify the file name,
and this will only unstage file1.txt.
So now if I run git status, you can
see I have one file in the staging area,
and file1.txt has been unstaged.
Now, it's easy to do this using BS code.
So if you want to just add
your files to staging area,
you can go to the source control
tab again and just click on plus.
It will add the files to the staging area.
And similarly, you can click
on minus, unstage changes,
and this will move them
back to the unstaged area.
You can also stage and
unstage all the files.
With the plus icon in front of the
changes, you can stage all of them together.
And to unstage, you can use
minus with unstage all changes.
And this will be bringing all
your files back to the unstage area.
So just feel free to use git restore
command or use VS Code to do the same.