You can use git reset command to
move files from stage to unstage.
You can do the same with git restore
as well, but the command is a bit long.
With git reset, you can simply
do git reset, the file name.
And if you want to move all of
your files to the unstaging area,
you can do git reset dot.
One interesting thing
which you can do with
the git reset command
is to remove commits.
So there can be two types of reset.
First one is that you can do a hard reset.
What a hard reset does
is that it will remove
the commits and don't keep your changes.
The command for it is git reset, the
commit hash, where you want to reset to,
and use hyphen hyphen hard.
Another one is a soft reset.
So this will remove the commits,
but all the changes will be
back in your working directory.
You can run git reset,
just the commit hash,
or you can also use hyphen
hyphen soft, but by default,
if you use git reset with commit
hash, it is going to do a soft reset.
git reset command is really
helpful if you accidentally
make a commit to a branch
and you want to remove it.
So this is the time when you would be
using git reset command a lot of times.
Now let's practice these three things.
Resetting your files from
staging area to unstaging area.
Desetting to a commit.
So we are back to the Git
video course repository.
In the file one, let's change
the text to Git reset demo.
Also, let's change the
file to Git reset demo two.
Now, in order to add these
files in the staging area,
we can do git add dot git status.
We have added it.
And now, in order to unstage it, it's
easier to do it with git reset dot.
Now if I do git status, the files
have been moved to unstaging area.
If you want to unstage just a
particular file, let's add it again,
and you can do git reset
and the name of the file.
Let's run the git status command again,
and you can see we have only moved
file1.txt into the unstaging area.
You could do the same
using git restore command,
which we talked in the previous section.
git restore, not a resort, git restore,
and hyphen hyphen staged, and the file name.
But this is a bit
inconvenient, or a bit long, I would say.
So mostly we can run the
git reset command to do this.
The second thing which we can do
with git reset is to remove commits.
So let's first make some commits.
Let's commit our files, git add all.
Git commit, minus m, reset demo1.
Let's change the files
again to file2, demo2, file1.
I've changed both the files again, and
let's commit them, git add all, git commit,
minus m, reset, demo two.
Now let's run git log.
Now we want to remove two previous
commits, resetDemo1 and resetDemo2.
So I will copy the hash
of one previous commit,
because this is the commit
where I want to move back to,
removing my top two commits.
So I'll copy the hash.
And I will do git reset to this commit.
Now I get the changes back, git status.
So there are changes in my working
directory, but if I check git log,
The commits have been removed.
There are no commits for git reset.
It's only for restore. So we have
successfully reset the commits,
So this is useful in case you made some
commits, but you want to make more changes.
So you can just reset them and make
final changes and then commit them again.
So this was a soft reset because the
changes are in your working directory.
If I commit it again, let's
change these files again.
First, git.
Okay, file.
Demo1 and Demo1.
Let's make two commits again.
Get commit minus M, reset Demo1.
Demo two, file two.
I'm making one more commit.
Demo two, file one.
So let's make another commit, git
add all, git commit, reset demo2.
Let's verify in the git log. I have
made two commits, demo1 and demo2.
Now I'm going to remove it, but
I'm going to do a hard reset.
So we do the same thing
just with the hard flag.
So copy the hash one before we want to
move to the restore demo three commit.
So I will copy the hash.
And here I can say git reset
hyphen hyphen hard and the commit hash.
So now if I check git log,
there are no commits for the reset.
But I also have lost all the
changes which I made because git status.
Doesn't show me any changes.
So I change these two files,
but I don't have those changes anymore.
So whenever you are
using git reset with heart,
just be conscious that you
will lose all the changes.
So in case you want to
still have those changes,
but you want to remove the
commits as well. So do a soft reset.