Git revert command also undoes the
commits, but instead of removing the commit,
it creates an additional
commit undoing that change.
The commit that is created
is called a revert commit.
So let's see what is the difference
between the reset and git revert,
because in the previous section, we
used git reset to remove our commits.
So with the git reset, let's say we
want to reset the two commits, C4 and C5.
With the git reset, the
head will move to C3.
Which means that we will not have
C4 and C5 in our commit history,
and that we also saw with the git log.
The issue with git reset is that
you can lose the shared history.
Let's say you had these five
commits in your master branch,
and somebody has created
another branch from the commit C4.
Now you do git reset and remove C4 and C5.
Now, the other person who is
working on the same project has C4
and C5 and has the work
which is based on these
two commits, but you have removed it.
And now if you push the removed commits,
then there will not be any
history regarding those commits.
So this can be a bit risky.
So instead of doing git reset,
if the commits are already pushed to
the remote server, we use git revert.
What Git revert does is that
it creates a new commit that
matches the historical
state of the previous commit.
Also, Git revert doesn't
change any project history.
So what Git revert will do in this
case is that it will create an additional
commit So this commit will
undo the changes of C4 and C5,
but in the history, you will still
see that you had C4 and C5 commit.
And now you have created a separate
commit with undoing those changes.
So this is a safe approach,
especially in case your commits
are pushed to the remote server.
So to sum up, Git revert does
not change the project history,
which makes it safe for
the commits which are
already published on
this shared repository.
Let's practice the Git revert command.
So let's go back to our project.
I will again change the two files.
Now instead of git restore,
let me do it git revert demo1
and git revert demo1 file2.
Let's commit this.
git commit minus am git revert
demo1 Let's check the git log command,
and we have made this git
reward demo one commit.
Now, what I want to do
is I want to remove this
commit because let's say
I accidentally made it
and I want to undo the
changes or I want to undo
the changes because
there was some bug here.
So I will just copy the commit hash.
Now, instead of doing git
reset, I will do git revert.
This hash belongs to the
commit which you want to revert.
So because I wanted to
revert the last commit,
so I copied the hash of the last commit.
So once I do git revert, now git asks me
to To write a message for the reverted commit, automatically
Git assigns a message.
It says revert and same
message which I had
provided to that commit.
So let's use the default message.
Now if I do git log, I have another
commit which reverts this commit.
So if you see file one and file
two, I have git restore demo 3,
but I had changed it to git revert demo 1.
So the changes are restored, but we
have also maintained the history.
We know that this commit was made to the
branch, but we also got the changes back.