To recap what we learned in this lesson,
so first we talked
about git checkout command.
Git checkout can be
used to do three things.
First, we can use the checkout
command to switch between the branches.
We can use git checkout to also
restore the changes in the files.
Also saw that with Git checkout,
you can also move to any commit,
but you would be in a detached head state.
Then we saw restoring
files with git restore.
With git restore, you can move to
the file version of any commit.
Also with the git restore,
we can unstage the files.
Then we saw that the Git reset,
how we can remove the commits.
There are two types of
resets we talked about.
One is the soft reset, in
which you will remove the commits,
but still have those changes
in your working directory.
There is a hard reset. In that
case, you will remove the commits,
but you will lose the changes.
Then we talked about reverting commits,
how we can undo the changes in
the commit with git revert command.
We also saw that git
revert command is safer,
especially when you have the commits
already pushed to the shared repo.
With git revert command, git
automatically creates a revert commit,
which has all the reverted changes.
Moving on to the exercise.
So what I want you to do is create
three commits in the master branch.
Permanently delete last two commits.
So you should not have those changes
in your working directory as well.
Third, create two more commits
and try to revert the last commit.