Welcome to lesson five,
Discovering Branches and Tags.
In this lesson, we'll
dive into branches and tags,
two powerful tools in
Git that help you organize
and manage your work more effectively.
These features are essential for
tracking different lines of development
and marking important
points in your project history.
We'll start by understanding what
branches are and how they work,
followed by a quick overview of the
concept of head and its role in Git.
Next, we'll explore the
essential Git commands.
We'll also take a look at
common branching strategies
to help you make the
most out of your workflow.
After that, we'll shift our focus to tags,
learning how to use tags for
marking releases in your project.
We'll wrap up with
summing up everything we
have learned in this
lesson and an exercise.
That's our journey for
this lesson. Let's jump in.