Before we discuss branches, let's
first talk about our commit process.
So when we are creating commits,
what we are actually doing is
linking commits to the previous commit.
So this is a linear flow
of commits because we are
putting commits on top
of the previous commit.
However, when we want to incorporate any
new feature without breaking existing code,
we need to work with branches.
What is a branch?
A branch represents an
independent line of development.
Let's say you want to work on a
user login feature in your project.
So what you will do is
that you will cut a new
feature branch in order to independently
work without breaking any
existing changes on the master branch.
All the commits that we
will do on user login
feature branch will
exist only on that branch.
This will make sure that we don't
affect the master branch changes.
Technically, a branch is nothing
but just a pointer to commits.
So when you create a branch, all what Git
needs to do is just create a new pointer.
It doesn't change the
repository in any way.
So let's say you had a master
branch, which is referring to commit C3.
Now, when you commit a feature branch,
You will say git branch feature branch.
Git will just create a new pointer for it,
and all the changes that you will do
will be a part of the feature branch.
So now the feature branch will be
pointing to the latest commit, which is C6,
but the master branch
would still be pointing to C3.
Talking more about the
master branch or main branch,
so this is a default branch which you
get when you create a new repository.
This is created by default by Git.
It's just like any other branch,
just that it's an initial branch.
GitHub now has changed the
naming of this branch to main branch.
So in a lot of places, you will see the
main name is getting used more often.
Also, it depends on the organization,
which name they want to
keep for their initial branch.
Usually we have main, master, and
trunk, some of the common names.
Let's go back to our project.
So we are right now on the main branch.
You can verify this with git status.
Let's make some changes to file one,
and let's say git branch demo one.
Let's add this commit, git
commit minus m branch demo.
Let's verify with the git log, and
we have made this branch demo commit.
Now, this is my main branch,
which already has some commits,
but now I want to make a new
feature, which is user login.
So I will create a new branch.
You can use git branch,
the name of the new branch.
Let's say user login.
We talked about that in
order to switch to the branch,
we can use git checkout command.
So we can use git checkout, the
name of the newly created branch.
So now if you make any changes,
it should be only on this branch.
So let's change the file one.txt.
Let's say user login feature.
And commit this, git add all, git
commit, minus m, user login demo.
Now, if I check my Git log,
so this was the branch demo commit
from where I created my new branch.
So this was the commit from
where I initialized my new branch.
And I made another commit,
which is user login demo.
Now, if I go back to the master,
git checkout, git checkout main,
I'm using main and master
interchangeably, so when I say master, it can be main,
so just make sure that
it's the same main branch.
Now, if I go back to
the main, checkout main,
and let's check the history with git log.
Here you can see there is no
commit related to user login feature,
which means that in my user login branch,
I can make as many commits
without affecting the main branch.
So in this way, I created an
independent line of development
for my feature by using a separate branch.