As you work more and
more with the branches,
you will see a term
showing up often during commits.
This term is head.
When you do git log,
you will see something
like the commit hash and also head master.
So far, we have seen head pointing to the
most recent commit in the master branch.
However, head is simply
a reference to a commit.
It can refer to any commit in any branch.
So when you do git
checkout your feature branch,
head would be pointing to the most
recent commit in your feature branch.
So let's say first I
was on the master branch.
My head would be pointing to the latest
commit on the master branch, which is C3.
Now let's say I created a feature
branch and made some commits on it.
So now my feature
branch is pointing to C6.
And if I do git checkout feature branch,
the head would be pointing to the latest
commit on feature branch, which is C6.
You can always switch back
head to some other branch.
Basically, if we do git checkout master
again, the head would be pointing to C3.
So why do we need head?
You can think of head as a name to
the most recent commit on your branch.
You can use head in your
commands like get reset,
where you want to reset
to the nth last commit.
And also you can use head in the commands,
in any command in which you
want to refer to the commits.
Let's see how that looks in the practice.
So let's go back to our repo and make
changes again, get our head demo one.
Let's make bunch of commits, get
commit minus am head demo one.
Let's make another commit, head
demo two and head demo three.
Let's check the Git log.
And now what I want to do is I want
to reset to my branch demo commit.
So basically I want to remove all
the three commits which I made.
One way we were doing it
was by copying the hash
of the commit where we want to reset back.
But instead of using this hash,
what we can tell Git is that we
want to delete The last three commits.
So basically, from the topmost
commit, we want to go three commits before.
So we say git reset.
Head, from the latest
commit, go three commits before.
And now if we do git log, you can see
all the three commits were removed.
So this is one way how you can
use head to go back to the commits,
because with the head, you can
always tell how many commits
before the last commit
you want to go back to.
Similarly for restoring files,
let's make those commits again.
Let's commit it, git add all, git commit.
Head demo one.
Let's make another commit.
Minus AM, head demo two.
Now in the Git log, I have two commits.
I want to restore the file to the
changes in the second last commit.
So, or let's say third last commit.
So I want to restore this
file's changes to the changes
which were there in the third last commit.
So what I can do is instead
of copying the hash again,
I'm going to play with the head.
So we saw we can use git
restore command to do it.
So git restore.
What's the source of the
file? So the source is head.
Go to commits before head.
And name of the file, which is file1.txt.
So we are back on the branch demo.
So this restored the file to the
commit to the second last commit version.
So this is how you can play with the head
whenever you want to refer to the commits.