Let's look at the commands of git branch.
So first command we have is to list
all the branches, which is git branch.
It tells you all the branches you have.
Next, we have git branch branch name,
which we have already seen
in the previous sections.
This command creates a new branch.
Then we have checkout or switch branch
command to switch to an existing branch.
You can either use git
checkout branch name,
or you can use git switch
to switch to another branch.
For creating a new branch and
switching to it immediately,
you can use git checkout
minus b and branch name.
In order to delete a branch,
you can use git branch hyphen
capital D along with the branch name.
Let's practice all these commands.
Let's move back to our repo.
So right now we are on main branch.
We have some changes. I will
just remove those changes.
I'm using git checkout command.
You can also use git restore command
to get rid of the changes you have.
So now I have no more changes.
So first of all, let's use git branch
command to see which all branches we have.
So I do have feed checkout and feed
user login, all of these branches.
In order to create a new branch,
we can simply do git branch
and the name branch-demo.
To verify if this branch was
successfully created or not,
you can run the git branch command
again, and it says feature branch demo,
so we already see the
branch which we have created.
So if I now want to move to this
feature branch, feature branch demo,
I will need to run git
checkout, the branch name.
Now if I run git status, it tells me
I'm on branch feature, branch demo.
So right now I had to run two commands.
So basically I created
a new branch and then
I run git checkout to move to that branch.
So we have a shortcut to do
both steps in one command.
Let's go back to the main branch.
Let's create another
branch and move to it.
So what we can write here is git
checkout minus b, the new branch name.
Branch demo two.
So what this command will do is
that it will create this branch,
feature branch demo two, and
also switches to this branch.
So now if I run this command,
it says switch to a new
branch feed slash branch demo two.
So this is a very handy,
so usually I personally run
this command whenever I
have to create a new branch.
And most of the time I
want to move to that branch
because I want to work on that branch.
Let's move back to the master branch.
Instead of checkout,
you can also use switch.
Switch domain.
Now let's say I want to
delete Couple of branches.
So what I will do is first I want
to list all the branches I have.
Let's say I want to
delete feed checkout demo too.
So I'll just copy it and do
git branch-t the branch name.
And now it tells me that you have
deleted branch checkout demo two.
If I want to delete
multiple branches together,
I can type all the branch names
together. So let's copy two branches.
Let's delete branch
demo and branch demo two.
So let's copy this and run the same
command with minus D, git branch minus D.
Name of the branches separated by space.
Now it says that you have deleted
branch demo and branch demo two.