Before we talk about branching strategies,
let's first talk about
the branching workflow.
While we are working on a project,
our end goal is to integrate our
changes with other team members' changes.
We have a mainline workflow
where we work with a single branch,
which is our main branch.
All the commits are
made to this main branch,
and everyone is working and
contributing to the same main branch.
The benefit of it is that because of
single branch, it's easy to track changes,
but there is also a risk
of shipping big changes.
Since everyone is
committing to the same branch,
there is a risk that something will
break, which makes it less resilient.
We also need to make sure that we
have a high quality test environment
to make sure that nothing
breaks on the main branch.
That is why we have
different types of branches.
So we have feature branch, which is
generally created for developing any feature.
Then we have a develop branch.
We have a hotfix or bugfix
branches, release branch for the releases,
and main branch, which
is the default branch.
Now, in terms of branches, we have some
branches which are long-running branches,
and the other branches
are short-lived branches.
Long running branches
are those branches which
stay throughout the course of development.
So we have a main branch,
which is the default branch.
And in some projects, we
also have a develop branch,
which is running
parallel to the main branch.
And it also persist as
a long running branch.
We also have some short lib branches,
like feature branch or hotfix branch.
So for the short lib branches,
they are there only for a short time.
Once their purpose is
finished, they are deleted.
For example, if you have
to create a new feature,
you would be creating a feature branch.
But once your feature
development has been completed
and it's merged to the main branch,
you would be deleting the feature branch.
Same goes with the hotfix or
bugfix branch. When the bug is fixed,
we would delete the bugfix.
And also with the release
branch, once the release is done,
we delete the release branch.
Now that you know about
different types of branches,
let's discuss the branching strategies.
So the most common branching
strategies we have are Git flow,
and the second one is GitHub flow.
First, let's talk about the Git flow.
In Git flow, we have two
long-running branches.
One is the main branch, which always
reflect the current production state.
There is a second long-running
branch, which is typically called Develop.
All the features start from the
Develop branch, and once they are developed,
they are merged back
into the Develop branch.
Develop branch is also the
starting point for new releases.
So developers open a new release branch
from the develop branch and work on that,
test it in case there are any bug fixes.
It is fixed in the release branch.
And once everything works and you are
confident that it's ready for production,
you merge your release branch into main.
As the last step, you
add a tag for the release
commit on main and
delete the release branch.
This type of strategy works
well for package softwares
or libraries with frequent releases.
However, for website
projects where releases
are very frequent, it
might be an overkill.
So the next strategy
we have is GitHub Flow.
In this strategy, we only have one
long-running branch, which is the main branch.
You will cut all the branches, be
it a feature branch, bug fix branch,
everything from the main branch.
Once your feature
development is completed,
you will merge it back to the main branch.
So this type of strategy is
easier and more straightforward.
I would suggest to use this if you
are working on a continuous delivery
project with short production
cycles and frequent releases.
So if your releases are like once in a
day or two times in a day, use GitHub Flow.
It's extremely lean and simple.
There is only one long running branch,
which is the default main branch.
Talking about branch naming conventions,
we already talked about some
conventions for the commits.
Similarly, we have some naming
conventions for the branches as well.
So firstly, all the branch
names should be in lowercase.
So for example, with feature new
login, it has to be in the lowercase.
If there are multiple words,
use hyphens to separate words.
Don't use any underscores or spaces.
Use alphanumeric characters, so no
special symbols like dollar, underscore.
Names should be descriptive.
You can also include Jira ID in the name.
Like for example, for user authentication,
you can name it as feature slash your
Jira ID, then the name of the feature.
We have couple of
examples for the branch names.
So it needs to be start
with the type of the branch.
So we can say feature slash Jira ID. Your
Jira ticket ID, then name of the feature.
For the bug fix, it
should start with like bug
fix slash ticket ID and the description.
For release, it's like release slash
hotfix hotfix slash docs doc slash.
If there is any library update,
you can name it as core slash
your ticket ID and the description.
Now we know what are branches
and how to create branches,
how to switch between different branches.
Let's see how we can move commits
from one branch to another branch.
For that, first do git
log and copy the commit
hash of the commit which you want to move.
Then switch to the branch
where you want to move the commit.
For switching, you can use git
checkout, name of the branch,
and then use cherry pick command,
git cherry pick the commit hash.
We are back to the repo.
So let's create a new
branch, git checkout, minus b.
I'm also moving to this
branch, cherry pick demo.
Notice the name of the branch.
So I have created feed.
We also use feed or
sometimes feature, both are fine.
And then I have separated the
cherry pick demo with hyphens.
Now let's make a commit,
cherry pick this commit.
Let's add this commit.
Git commit minus m cherry pick demo.
Verify it from the git log.
So this is the commit that we
want to move to the main branch.
So first I will copy this hash.
Now I switch to the main
branch, git checkout main.
Check the git log. So right
now, we don't have that commit.
The last commit we have is head-demo-to.
In order to move the commit,
actually to copy the commit,
let's run this git
cherry-pick and the commit hash.
Now, if we run git log, we have
cherry pick demo commit on this branch.
So this is how you can copy commits
from one branch to another branch.