So tags are basically
bookmarks on your commit so that
you can easily find them and
reuse if needed in future.
They are mainly used to mark
the releases so that you can
easily move back to the
previous release if required.
There are mainly two types of tags.
First one is the lightweight tag.
In this tag, you only add
a tag name to the commit
without adding any additional information.
Then we have annotated tags.
In this, you store additional
information, including the tagger's name, email,
and date, as well as the tag message.
In order to create a lightweight tag,
you can write git tag and name of the tag.
For the annotated tag, you can write
git tag minus a to tell that it's an
annotated tag with the tag name
minus m and description about the tag.
In order to list all the tags,
you can use git tag command.
Then to push your tags, you can
use git push origin name of the tag.
For deleting the tag, you
can use git tag minus t.
This time minus t is with
small d, and then name of the tag.
This will delete the tag
on your local machine,
but if you want to delete it
from the remote server as well,
you need to push the deleted tag.
So for that, you need to do git push
origin hyphen hyphen delete tag name.
Let's practice all of this.
Let's create tags, list tags,
and also see how we can
push and delete tags.
Let's go back to our repository.
Now, why would you need a tag?
It is basically to mark the releases.
So let's say I In my main
branch, I have a couple of features,
and I want to mark this
commit as the release one,
which means that till this
commit, it's the release one.
So release one has all the
commits till this last commit.
So what I can do is I can
bookmark the last commit with git tag.
Firstly, I need to create a tag.
So we can create a lightweight tag.
Let's say git tag v1.0 or just v1.
Now, if I do git log, it tells me that,
okay, this commit is associated with a tag.
Now, if I make more
commits to this, let's say
tag demo1, git add, git commit, tag demo.
Let's check git log, and now I
have this commit with the tag v1,
so it's easy for me to go
back to this release one
in case anything
breaks in the next release.
It's always easier to roll back to the
previous release with the help of tags.
Let's create some more commits.
Commit "-am tag-demo2".
This time I will create an
annotated tag, so git Tag minus A.
So we tell what is the name
of the tag. Let's call it v2.
And then we also need to
specify the description.
So this is release two.
Now let's do git log.
So now I have two tags.
This V1 tag is for release
one, and then I have V2 tag,
which is associated
with tag demo to commit.
In order to see all the tags you
have, you can use git tag command,
and it will list all the tags.
Now, if I want to see what the tag
has, I can use git show name of the tag.
Let's see what v2 tag has.
Now, it tells me that the
tag name is v2, who tagged it,
and what was the
description when it was added,
and also it tells me what was
the commit on which it was tagged.
Similarly, if we want to see v1, let's
see git show v1, and in the v1, yeah,
we have the commit, but we don't
have additional information like
description and other things
because this was a lightweight tag,
so we don't have extra information.
Now let's say something broke in V2 and
I want to roll back to my V1 release.
So I can do is move to the V1
tag by using git checkout command.
Here I will use the tag name V1
because I want to move back to the V1 tag.
So now we have moved to a tag.
That is why Git is telling me that
you are in a detached head state.
So this state comes when
you are not on a branch.
If you move to a commit, Git will tell
you the same, that you are in detached head.
So now whenever we want to work
from here, we need to create a branch.
So we will do git checkout
minus b release one, let's say.
And now if I do git log, this
has all the commits till v1.
And if I want to deploy the release
one again, I can deploy this branch.
Lastly, let's see how to delete tags.
So let's move back to the
main branch, git checkout main.
So we have V1 and V2 tags,
let's delete the V1 tag.
Get tag minus T and name of the tag.
So this says deleted tag V1.
Right now, this tag, we had not pushed
it, so this only existed on our local.
If the tag was already pushed, we
would have to also push the deleted tag.
So that was about
tags, how to create tags,
when to use tags, and how to delete tags.