Let's recap what we
learned in this lesson.
So firstly, we talked about
branches, what are branches,
and how to work with
different types of branches,
like feature branch, bug fix branch.
We also discussed the concept of head.
We talked about that head
always refers to the latest
commit on the branch on which you are on.
If you switch the branches,
then head will represent the latest
commit on the newly switched branch.
We talked about some branch
commands, like how to create a branch,
how to delete a branch, and how to
switch between the different branches.
We talked about branching strategies,
mainly two types of branching strategies,
Git flow and GitHub flow.
Git flow is used in the
projects where releases are
less frequent, like
months, one or two months.
However, for website projects
where the releases are very frequent,
like once a day or two times a day,
you can use GitHub Flow because
that is more easier to manage.
We talked about what are
tags, why do we need tags,
and how to use them for releases.
We saw there were two types of
tags. One is the lightweight tag.
Another one is annotated
tags with more description.
Coming to the exercise now, You are asked
to develop user authentication feature,
follow all the steps which are required.
So first you need to create a
branch, use branch naming conventions,
create two files,
authentication.js, loginform.html, make a commit,
and also use conventional commits.
In the part two from the GitHub
UI, create a separate branch,
which should be a bug fix branch
in the authentication feature.
Use a proper branch name,
then make a commit and
cherry pick that bug fix commit
from that branch in your
authentication feature branch.