Welcome to lesson six,
merging and rebasing in Git.
In this lesson, we'll explore
two fundamental Git concepts
that help you integrate
changes from different branches,
which is merging and rebasing.
Mastering these tools will
allow you to handle collaboration
and streamline your project
history more effectively.
We'll begin with theory
and concepts behind merging,
followed by hands-on practice
with merge commands in Git.
Then we'll switch to rebase,
starting with a deep dive into theory
and practical application of rebasing.
After that, we will
compare and contrast the two
approaches to help you
decide which one to use.
Then we'll learn how to
create pull requests,
an essential part of
collaboration in Git projects.
Finally, we wrap up with a
summary and an exercise.
That's the plan for this
lesson. Let's get started.