In our previous lesson, we talked about
branches and why do we need branches.
Now, as we work on a feature,
most likely we would be
creating a separate branch
which would contain those
feature-related changes.
But eventually, what we want
to do is we want to integrate
our work with the rest of our team's work.
In order to do that, there is a main
branch where everyone integrates their work to.
So you would be merging
your feature branch into the
main branch after
completing the feature request.
Now, how do we merge?
In order to merge your changes,
go to the branch where you
want to merge your changes into.
For example, let's say you want to merge
your feature branch into master branch.
For that, go to master branch
with command git checkout master,
Run git merge feature branch.
This will merge feature
branch into the master branch.
Now one thing to note here is
that although we are merging
in this example directly
into the master from the CLI,
but we never usually do it like that.
There are better ways to do
it by creating a pull request,
which we will get into
in the later section.
Now, there can be
different scenarios while merging.
The first scenario we are going to
talk about is a fast-forward merge.
Let's take an example.
Let's say we are on master branch, and
our master branch is pointing to commit C1.
Now we want to work on a feature,
so we will create a feature branch,
which is pointing to C1 right now.
And now we will switch
to the feature branch,
and start to make commits
on this feature branch.
Now I'm finished with my
feature branch changes,
and we want to merge the
feature branch back to the master.
So we'll do git checkout master
and git merge feature branch.
Now in this case, it is a special case
of merging where the branch you branched
off has no further commits than
what you did in the new branch.
For example, in this case,
there were no more commits in the
master branch when you started to merge.
The master branch was
still pointing to commit C1.
Let's see what happens for a merge where
we have different commits. In example,
we have a master branch
which is pointing to commit C1,
and our feature branch
is pointing to commit C3.
Now somebody comes and make two
more commits in the master branch.
Now our master branch is
pointing to commit C5.
In this case, when I try to merge
using git merge feature branch,
it cannot be a fast forward
merge because both master
and feature branch have different commits.
Master branch has C4 and C5,
whereas feature branch has C2 and C3.
So in this case, what Git does is that it
will automatically create another commit,
which is called merge commit with the
name merge branch and name of the branch.
Now, our master branch will be
pointing to the newly created merged commit.
This merge commit will
contain all the changes
which are related to the feature branch.
What is a merge commit?
Git creates this commit
automatically while merging
two branches when fast
forward is not possible.
This merge commit will contain the
changes related to both the branches.
There can be scenarios where you have
conflicts while merging the branches,
which are known as merge conflicts.
Conflicts occur when the same
file is changed in two branches.
In that case, we need
to resolve the conflicts
between the branches
in order to merge them.
Let's take an example.
So our master branch now
is pointing to commit C5,
Whereas our feature branch
is pointing to commit C3.
Now in the commit C4, file A
is changed in master branch,
and in the feature
branch, also file A is changed.
Now in both the branches, we have
changed the same file, In this case,
when we try to merge feature
branch into master branch,
there will be merge conflict
because file A has different
content in master branch
and in feature branch.
This is how the conflicts look like.
In the conflicts you have head,
this content between the
arrows and the hyphens means
the content already
exists in the current branch.
This is your division line,
which define the division between the
conflicting changes between branches.
The last section represents the content
from the branch you are trying to merge,
which is your feature branch.
Now we know what a merging is, fast
forward merge, as well as three-way merge,
and we have also talked
about merge conflicts.
Let's see everything in
practice in the next section.