Let's go back to our repository.
So right now we are on main git
status. We are on main branch.
Let's check the last two
commits. On our main branch,
we have tagdemo and
tagdemo2 as our last commits.
Now I'll create a new
feature branch, git checkout,
and I will be moving to this branch.
Feature merge demo.
Let's change the file one dot txt.
I'll make it merge demo commit one.
Let's make a commit, git add all, git
commit, minus m, merge demo, commit one.
Let's make another commit.
We'll use the same
command, and I will use "-am".
This adds and creates commit together.
Merge commit demo two.
And then I do git log, and
here we have the two commits.
Now I'm going to merge this
feature branch into main branch.
For that, I will first need
to move to the main branch.
Git checkout main.
Now I do git merge.
The name of the branch
which I want to merge,
which in my case is feed slash merge demo.
Once I run this command, you must have
noticed that it is a fast forward merge.
The reason for that was that
there were no more commits
in the main branch when
I started to merge this.
So now my commit history
looks like the tag demo two,
and then merge commit
one, merge demo commit two.
So what Git had to do
was just put the commits
of the feature branch on the main branch,
and that is why it was
a fast-forward merge.
Next we'll see the three-way merge.
Let's create another branch.
Git checkout minus B.
Feature three-way merge.
I'll make two commits
in this branch as well.
Three-way merge.
Commit one.
Git add all.
Git commit minus m.
Three-way merge, commit one.
Let's do another commit as well.
Get add all.
Get commit, three-way merge, commit two.
Now before merging, What
I want to do is I want
to make additional
commits to the main branch.
So I will go to main
branch and change or create
another file. Let's create file3.txt.
File 3 created to show merge commit.
git add all, git commit,
minus m, file 3 changes.
So now our main branch has
this commit file three changes.
And if I go back to my feature branch,
get checkout feature three-way merge.
My feature branch does not
know anything about file three.
So the commit which I made to the
master branch is not in this feature branch.
So now both the branches
have different commits.
Let's see what happens
when I try to merge the
feature branch into
master branch in this case.
I will go to my main
branch, git checkout main, and
I will do git merge,
feature three-way merge.
So here, now Git is trying
to create a merge commit,
and it asks you to
enter the commit message.
You can enter your own commit message,
or just choose the
default message created by Git.
So I will do colon Q,
exit it so that I can
choose the one which is added by the Git.
Now let's check the history.
And in Git log, we have a merge commit,
which says merge branch
feature three-way merge.
This merge commit was created because
both the branches had different commits
when I was trying to merge the
feature branch into the main branch.
Let's also talk about conflicts.
Let's create a new branch.
Merge conflicts.
Let's change the file
one, merge conflicts.
Let's commit this file,
merge conflicts demo.
I forgot to add, so let's add
it, and then make a commit.
Now, in this branch, I have
changed the file1.txt content.
I will go to the main
branch and change the same file.
So let's go to main.
In file one, let's do a change.
Main branch file one content.
And make a comment, comment.
Now in this case, both the
branches, feature branch and main branch,
has different content in file1.txt.
So in both the cases,
the same file is changed.
Now when I try to merge the
feature branch, merge conflicts,
Git is going to show me the conflicts
that in, we talked about that head.
It tells you the current branch
changes, which is our main branch.
So it says you have main branch file one
content, this text in your main branch,
and in your feature branch, you
have merge conflicts demo text.
Now you can either accept changes from
your current branch or incoming changes,
or you can also accept both the changes.
You can resolve these changes
using Visual Studio Code Editor.
So here I will do accept both changes.
Once you have resolved the
changes, you need to do git add all,
and then do git merge continue.
Since this was a three-way merge,
git will ask you the
message for the merge commit.
You can choose the default
message or type your own.
In this case, I'm choosing the
default one, colon Q, exit it.
Let's check our log, and
there is a merge commit,
but we have successfully
merged our feature branch,
and now this file one
has both the changes from
the main branch as well
as the feature branch.
So right now we saw
three cases while merging.
The first one we saw
was fast-forward merge,
in which there were no more changes
in the main branch while merging.
So Git could simply
apply all the changes of
feature branch on top of the main branch.
This is what is fast forward merge.
But in a lot of scenarios,
actually maximum scenarios,
people would be
working on the main branch.
So by the time when you come to
merge your feature branch into main,
there are likely to be
more commits in the main.
In that case, Git will
create a merge commit to dissolve
the different commits
in both the branches.
Lastly, we also talked
about merge conflicts.
Merge conflicts occur when you
change same file in both the branches.
So while merging, it does not
know which version to accept.
So right now we have seen how to
merge our feature changes into the main.
So we are integrating our feature
branch into the main branch using merge,
but we also have another
way to do it using rebase.
In the next section, we'll talk about
that, how to use rebase to do the same.