So far, we saw in order to
integrate our feature changes into master,
we can check out to master branch
and do git merge feature branch.
We also saw that merging also creates
additional merge commit to complete the merge.
However, as an alternative to merging,
you can use rebase to
merge the feature branch
into main using the following commands.
In this case, you will first
check out to your feature branch,
then do git rebase master.
Let's understand this
better using an example.
Let's say we are on master branch, and
master branch is pointing to commit C1.
Now we want to work on our feature branch,
so we will create a
feature branch from C1,
and we'll switch to this feature
branch, and create more commits.
So now our feature branch is on C3,
whereas our master branch is on C1.
Now we made two more
commits to the master branch.
So now master branch is
pointing to commit C5.
If I want to merge my
feature branch into master branch,
one way is that I can go to the master
branch and do git merge feature branch.
In this case, git will create a merge
commit because this is a three-way merge.
Alternatively, what you can do is
that you can go to your feature branch,
git checkout feature branch,
and then run git rebase master.
What rebase will do is that it will
take master branch changes, which is,
in this case, is C4 and C5, and put
feature branch commits on top of it.
So in this case, with rebase, Git
will put C2 and C3 on top of C4 and C5.
To recap, when we do git checkout
feature branch and git rebase main,
This moves the entire feature branch
to begin on the tip of master branch,
effectively incorporating all
the new commits in the master.
Now, when we go to the master
and do git merge feature branch,
it will be a fast forward merge
because there were no more commits
in the master when we were
trying to merge the feature branch.
And now we don't have additional
merge commit also in the history.
This makes Git history
cleaner and easier to view.