Let's practice the rebase commands.
We would be rebasing
feature branch on main.
Then we will also see how to
handle conflicts with rebase.
And finally, we'll see
how the history looks
different than merging in case of rebase.
Let's go back to our editor.
And now we want to
create another feature branch
get checkout minus P feature rebase demo.
Let's create a new file.
Dot TXT.
So rebase demo commit one.
Let's commit these changes. Git add all,
git commit minus m, rebase demo commit one.
Let's make another commit with minus am.
So we have made two commits,
rebase demo one and rebase demo two.
Let's go back to our master
branch, git checkout main,
and let's make another
commit in the main branch.
So I will say file, Four dot
txt changes from another person.
Let's commit these changes.
Commit minus m added file four.
Now if I do git log, it
has this additional commit
which my feature branch has no idea about.
Now, if I want to merge my
feature branch into main branch,
one way is that I can do git merge and my
feature branch, which is the base demo.
This command will merge the
feature branch into main branch,
but since this is not going
to be a fast-forward merge,
Git will create an additional
commit, which is a merge commit,
because both these
branches have different commits.
Instead, what we can do is we
can go to our feature branch,
git checkout rebase demo, and this
time we can say git rebase main.
What rebase means is that we want to
change the base of the feature branch,
because when we created this feature
branch, it was on a different commit.
Afterwards, there were more
commits in the main branch,
and we want to incorporate those commits.
So with this command,
with git rebase main,
what git will do is that it will
pull the new changes in main and
put the changes in the feature
branch on top of the main commits.
So we do git rebase main.
And now you can see we
already have file four.
If we do git log, then we have added,
we have this commit added file four.
And one thing you would notice
is that how the history looks.
Because we have a commit from main,
and then we have the
commits from this feature branch.
So the commit into this feature branch
was put on top of the commits on main.
Now, if we merge, in order to merge, we
want to go back to our master branch,
which is our main branch.
And now if I run git
merge my feature branch.
In this case, it will be a fast
forward merge because now I have
incorporated the changes of main
branch into the feature branch.
So you can see Git says it's
a fast forward merge because
main did not hide any more
commits when I was merging.
Let's check the Git log.
And now you can see how
clear the history looks.
We have main commit, then we have
both the commits of our feature branch.
There is no additional
merge commit created by Git.
Let's also see the
conflicts while using DBase.
Let's create another feature branch
with get checkout minus P rebase demo two.
Let's call it with feet.
In this case, now
let's change the file one.
And here I will see, I will change it
to rebase conflicts demo commit one.
Let's do git add all, git commit
minus m, rebase conflicts, commit one.
Let's go back to our main
branch and change the same file.
So file one, let's
change it to something else.
Rebase conflicts because of main changes.
Let's add it, git commit minus m.
Let's just give it any
message, conflicts from main.
Now what we have done is
that we have changed the same
file, which is
file1.txt, in both the branches.
Main has this text, whereas the
feature branch has a different text.
Now let's go back to our
feature branch, rebase.
Demo to get checkout.
Now, in order to run rebase, we need
to run this command get rebase main.
Now, since we have changed the
same file in both the branches,
we should see some conflicts.
Okay, so now Git is saying that you have
conflicts because in the current branch,
you have the changes which are in green.
It's the opposite.
In the green it says the conflicts
which are coming from the main branch,
and in the blue it says the
conflicts which are in the current branch.
We will resolve these changes.
You can choose whichever to accept.
Let's say we want to
also keep the main changes.
So we can do accept both changes.
Or if we just want to keep the current
change, then we can do accept current change.
Now we will do git add all and
git rebase hyphen hyphen continue.
Git will ask you to rewrite the message.
Let's use the default one for now.
And now we have resolved the changes.
So we have the file1.txt
with our accepted changes.
So this is how conflicts
look like while rebasing.
It's very much similar to the merging.
It's just on the different branch.
So once you resolve the changes,
it's easier to merge back to main.
So for that, we can do git checkout
main, and then do the same thing, git merge.
Feature rebase-demo2.
This will again be a fast-forward merge.
And then we have the commits
from the rebase-demo2 branch.
So this was about how
to use rebase when you
want to integrate your changes into main.
The main point here is
that when you use rebase,
there is no additional merge commit,
which makes your history looks
way cleaner and more linear.