Let's recap the differences
between merging and rebase.
So we saw that with merging,
it's going to be a three-way merge,
which means Git is going to
create an additional merge commit.
However, with rebasing,
no merge commit is created
because it's always a fast-forward merge.
Now, whether to use merge or rebase,
it depends on your
personal preference or also on
what you have decided as
a team in your project.
Some people like to see the
cleaner history, so they prefer rebase.
However, there are different benefits of
using merge, so some people prefer merging.
The major benefit of rebasing is that
you get a much cleaner project history.
There are no unnecessary merge
commits required by git merge.
So git rebase creates a linear
history which makes it easy to
navigate the project with git
log or git bisect commands.
However, there are also some
pitfalls using git rebase.
Since git rebase rewrites the history,
it can be dangerous in
terms of collaboration if
you don't follow the
golden rules of rebasing.
The first rule we have is that you
never use git rebase on public branches,
which means you never do git checkout
master and do git rebase feature branch.
Why is that?
Because your master branch
has hundreds of commits,
and a lot of other people are
also working on the master branch.
Now, when you do git
rebase feature branch,
what it will do is that it
will take all the commits of the
master branch and put it on
top of your feature branch.
And the problem with that is that
it only happen in your repository.
All the developers who are still
working on the original main branch,
they will have a very different history.
Since Rebase results in brand new commits,
Git will think that
your main branch history
has diverged from
everybody else's history.
Also, when you try to push the
master to remote with git push master,
git will prevent you from doing so
because it conflicts with the remote main branch.
If you did git push
master hyphen hyphen force,
it will override the remote master with
your rebase branch, which is not good.
So the second rule is that before you
run git rebase, always ask yourself,
is anyone else looking at that branch?
So for example, with the main branch,
because other people are also
working on the main branch,
don't do git rebase on the main branch.
Also, with the feature branches,
if you think couple of more people
are working on the same feature branch,
then don't do git rebase
in that feature branch.
Only do the git rebase in the
branches where you are working on,
and you know that the rebase is
going to be safer in that case.