We talked about that our
end goal is to integrate
our work with the rest of our coworkers.
We saw two techniques to do it
using merging and using rebasing.
So far, we have been merging our
changes directly to the master branch,
but this is not the best way
because it doesn't leave a
scope for your changes to be
reviewed by your teammates.
There is another way to merge
your changes into the master branch,
which is by creating pull requests.
Now, pull requests are
not a feature of Git,
but is provided by Git hosting
platforms like GitHub, GitLab, or Bitbucket.
The main goal of pull request is to
merge your changes into the main branch.
The problems with merging directly
into the master are it's less resilient.
Also, there is no way to get feedback.
So in case there is
some issue with your code,
there's nobody to tell you that
you need to make these changes.
Also, if people are merging
directly into the master,
you will end up having way more conflicts.
So why create pull requests?
With pull requests, you
can invite other people
to review your work and give you feedback.
Once your changes have been approved,
your branch can be merged to master.
So without pull request,
you would jump right into
merging your feature
branch into the main branch.
However, with pull requests,
you will invite the reviewers to
provide feedback before merging.
Once they approve, it's ready
to be merged to the main branch.
Let's practice how to create pull
requests, how to merge a pull request,
and also see how to resolve
conflicts in the pull requests.
Let's go back to our
video course repository.
I want to create a new
feature branch for pull requests.
Let's say I create a new branch, git
checkout, minus b, feed pull request.
Now let's make some
changes to this branch.
Let's create a new file, file3.txt, and
add some changes, pull request, commit one.
Let's make the commit, git
commit minus m, commit one.
So now I want to merge this
branch to the main branch.
One way is that I go to the
main branch, git checkout, main,
and here I can do git
merge, feature pull request.
Now, this is risky, especially if
you're working in a project in a company,
So we never really run the merge
command directly into the CLI.
And most of the time it's also restricted.
So instead of merging
directly into the main,
what we will do is that we
will create a pull request.
Now how to create a pull request?
Let's go back to our feature
branch, get checkout, feature branch.
And here I will do git push because
first I need to push this branch to remote.
Now git tells me that this
branch does not exist on origin.
So I will need to run this command.
Okay, so now my branch is
pushed along with my changes,
and here I have the
link of the pull request.
So it says create a
pull request from feature
pull request on GitHub
by visiting this URL.
Let's copy this URL.
So this is a page where
we create a pull request.
Now there are different
conventions how to create a pull request.
Like for the title, it also should
start with your type of pull request.
So we can do like this feature.
This pull request is for
the feature pull requests
or learning to create pull requests.
Then you write the description.
In the title, you can also mention your
ticket ID, like which is this ticket,
and then write more description about it.
There is also a template for the
description, how to write good pull requests.
So one thing you would write is the
summary, like what is this pull request about?
Like for example, Learning pull requests.
What are the changes? So then you
can mention what are the changes.
Changes in file one.
Whenever you're working on a real
feature, often you have a couple of changes.
Like for example, if you're
working on a user login feature,
you will have a login screen. You will
have a couple of more things related to API.
So you can mention all the
changes in the changes section.
Then add the screenshots.
And add the relevant testing
strategy, how to test this feature.
And you can also write
additional notes in case
the reviewer needs to
know anything special.
Now, why do we create
pull requests like this?
It's because your pull requests are meant
to be reviewed by your other coworkers.
And if you provide nice
description about it, it's easier to review.
So now there's a button
to create pull requests.
Every platform has their own UI,
but all the platforms provide the
same functionality. Like for example,
you can add reviewers who
reviews this pull request.
Then you can also assign
the pull request to yourself.
You can provide labels, like for example,
if you're working on a frontend or a bug,
you can provide label as bug,
or if it is a frontend feature,
you can label it as
frontend or label it as backend.
So labels are really
helpful for the filtering.
Now let's click on create pull request.
So now it has created my pull
request, and you can see in the commits,
I can see which is the commit.
Also in the files
changed, I can see the changes.
So this is easier for the
reviewer to review your changes.
Your reviewer will most likely be
reviewing the changes in the files change section.
In case there are more files,
it will show more All the files
with the changes in all those files.
So let's go back. And now what you
can do is you can merge the request.
Here you have a couple of options. You
can create a merge commit, simply merge.
I will use the first
one. So merge pull request.
Confirm merge.
Now, in order to verify whether the
changes are merged in the main branch,
let's go back to our main branch.
Let's go back to our editor, and
here I will move to the main branch.
Let's pull the changes.
And now you can see the
file tree is created,
and this has content
pull request commit one.
So we got the changes
related to pull requests.
So this is how you merge
by creating pull requests.
Let's also see how we can get
conflicts in our pull requests.
Now we know that in
order to get conflicts,
we need to have different content in
the same file in the two branches.
Let me create a new branch.
Get checkout minus B. Pull request.
Conflicts.
Let's change the file one.
Full request.
Let's make a commit,
git add all, git commit.
Conflicts, commit one.
Let's go back to our main.
Or let's make the changes
in main directly from the
GitHub so that we don't
have to push those changes.
I can just go to the
branch, and here I will create,
or I will change in the
file1.txt. Let's edit this file.
Changes from main.
Okay, let's commit these changes.
And now the point is that we have
changed file one in both the branches.
So file one is
different in main branch and
file one is different
in our feature branch.
Now, in order to merge, I first will
Pushed my branch on GitHub. For that,
I need to run this command again. So
now there is a link, and let's go to it.
Open a merge request.
I'm not adding any particular template,
so we'll just add a normal description.
We are with conflicts.
Let's create the pull request.
Now in this case, it says that you had
tagged demo two and you changed with,
you replaced the content
with pull request changes one.
So it shows the changes in the files.
Okay, so now it clearly says that this
branch has conflicts that must be resolved.
Now you can resolve conflicts with GitHub,
but let's see how to do
it from the CLI itself.
So how I will resolve these changes.
The changes are first of all,
because both the branches have
different content in file1.txt.
So first, I need to go to
the main branch, git checkout
main, and pull the
changes, pull the latest changes.
So now I have the changes
which are made by another person.
I will go to the feature branch.
Now here, I can use the rebase
strategy, git checkout, Rebase main.
You can also use a merging strategy,
but I will be using git rebase here.
So once I do git rebase, it tells me
that which changes you want to keep.
I want to keep both
the changes, let's say.
So I will just add and do git
rebase hyphen hyphen continue.
And now I have the
changes from the main branch,
so I can push these changes because
now these conflicts have been resolved.
Because we used rebase, we will have
to use git push hyphen hyphen force.
Let's go back to our pull request.
And you can see there
are no conflicts now.
Let's see how we can resolve conflicts
using merge. So right now we used rebase.
So we pulled the latest changes of
main into our branch by using rebase,
but you can also use merge.
Let's see how to do that.
So first let, let me go
again and Change another file.
Let's say this time I change file two.
I will change the text and
now I have more changes.
So now file2.txt is
changed in the main branch.
I will change the same
file in our feature branch.
So let's go back to our repository and
change the file to pull request conflicts.
I will add the file, make the commit.
Commit to.
So in this commit, I have changed file to,
and I know the file to is
changed on the main branch.
First, let's push the
changes on our feature branch.
Let's go to the pull request.
So this is our pull request.
GitHub is evaluating that this branch
has conflicts that must be resolved.
You can also resolve it from here, but
let's see how to do it from the CLI.
Let's go back to our repository,
and this time I'm going to
merge the changes of main.
First of all, right now
when I do git merge main,
It will not bring the new
changes because my local main branch
does not have the updater
changes from the remote server.
So first I need to go
to my main branch and
update my main branch
with the new changes.
So I'll do git pull so that now my
local main branch has the updater changes.
Let's go back to the feature branch
Now, instead of doing now git
rebase main, I will do git merge main.
We have not moved to the feature
branch, so let's move to the feature branch.
Git checkout.
I have created aliases, which I
already taught in the previous section.
So this makes it easy to write commands.
Okay.
So now in this case, I'm
going to do git merge main.
There are conflicts, of course,
that's why we need to resolve it.
And let's accept our
teammates changes this time.
Okay. So I have accepted
this change and do git add all,
and then git merge hyphen hyphen continue.
So whenever we are done with our
conflicts, we are, we have accepted the changes.
Then we need to run git add
all and git merge continue.
In this case, there is
going to be a merge commit.
So you can see there are changes.
There are changes from this
feature branch and there is additional
merge commit created because we
resolved the conflicts using merge.
Now let's do git push.
Let's go back to our pull request.
And now the conflicts have been resolved,
and you can click on Merge Pull Request,
and this will merge your pull request.
So this is how you create a pull request,
and this is how you resolve
conflicts in your pull request.
You can either use merge or you
can use rebase to resolve conflicts,
whichever works better for you.
When you will use rebase, there will
not be any additional merge commit.
However, the history would be different.
So you will often have to do
git push hyphen hyphen force.
So make your decision according to what
you think suits your scenario the best.