To recap what we learned in this
lesson, so first we talked about merging,
how we can merge our
features into the main branch.
Then we talked about how we can
use rebase to integrate our changes.
The benefit we saw with the rebase
is that there is no merge commit,
and we can update our feature branch
with the latest commits on the main branch.
Then we also saw how to handle conflicts
while merging and also while rebasing.
Finally, we talked about pull request.
We saw that directly merging
to master is not a great idea.
It can be risky and it doesn't
give your peers to review your code.
So that is why we create pull requests.
Pull requests will give a
chance to your peers to review
your code and then
suggest any feedback you have.
Going to the exercise,
I want you to create
a new Git repository
with name git-workshop,
create index.html file
with content hello world,
and push changes to your remote repo.
After you are done with creating a
repo, I want you to practice merging.
So create a feature branch with name
feature merge exercise from master.
Edit your index.html file
with changing text in the body.
You can choose to create a new file as
well. It depends on what you want to do.
Make a commit, go to master, this
time make two commits into the master.
Go to the feature branch and
merge master in your feature branch.
Now you should see the master
commits along with the merge commit.
I also want you to practice
rebase, so this is the next part.
For rebase, create a feature
branch again from the master,
edit your index.html file, make a
commit, go to master, make two commits again,
Go to the feature branch, and this
time use rebase in your feature branch.
There should be a difference in
the history that you should see.
Your commits would be
on top of the master,
and there would be no
additional merge commit.
Finally, also practice pull requests.
With the pull request,
part one is that you create
a bug fix branch from the master branch.
Change the text in index.html to
hello world from your country.
Push your branch to remote,
and this time merge the branch
to master using the pull request.
Verify the changes in master
branch and use git pull to see
if the changes have been
updated in your local repository.
As a part two, create
another branch from master,
change the text again,
and commit your changes.
Go back to the master
and change the text again.
Now go to your feature branch
and push your branch to remote.
Create a pull request. Now this time you
should see some conflicts while merging.