Welcome to Lesson 7,
Learning Git Advanced.
In this lesson, we'll tackle some
advanced Git features that will enhance
your workflow and give you more
control over your project history.
These tools are particularly
useful when managing complex
changes or cleaning up
your Git commit history.
We'll start by learning how to use
git stash to temporarily save changes,
followed by exploring
how to squash multiple
commits into one to
keep your history clean.
After that, we'll dive
into interactive rebase.
And finally, we
explore git reflog command,
which lets you track changes in your
git history and recover from mistakes.
Then we wrap up with a
summary of everything
we have learned, followed by an exercise.
That's the roadmap for this lesson. Let's
dive into these advanced git techniques.