Stash is a place where you can
temporarily save the changes you made to your working
directory so that you can work on
something else and come back to it later.
It's very useful when you have to
quickly switch branches to work on something
else while you were already in
the middle of changing a file.
Let's take an example.
Let's say you were working on a
feature and you have some uncommitted files.
Now, maybe there was a bug in master,
so you have to quickly go back
to the master to fix the bug.
In order to do that, you will run
command-git checkout master, but in this case,
there can be two possible scenarios.
Since you have some uncommitted files,
if those uncommitted files are new
set of files which are not on master,
you would move to the
master because there are
no conflicts along with
the set of new files.
Another case is that you have modified
the set of files which are already on master.
In this case, when you try to move
to master using git checkout command,
git will give you an error that your
local changes would be overwritten by checkout.
Please commit your changes or
stash them before switching branches.
So here you have one option that you
can commit your changes Or you can also
do is that you can put your
changes in a special place called stash.
So you can keep your changes on the
stash and move to the master branch,
fix the bug which is in
the master branch, come back
to the feature branch,
and apply the changes.
So Git stash is really handy if you
are in the middle of making changes in
a feature branch and you have to
quickly switch to a different branch.
How do we use git stash?
So we can use command git stash push.
This will push the entry into the
stash with all the uncommitted files.
Then you can use git stash pop,
which will take out the changes
from the stash and apply them.
We also have git stash apply.
It also applies thick stash changes,
but preserve the entry in the stash.
It is useful if you want to apply
the same changes to multiple branches.
Please note that git stash command does
not push the untracked files to stash.
In order to push all the files to
stash, including untracked ones,
use command git stash push minus u
minus k. Let's go back to our repo.
I will create a new feature
branch, git checkout-p feeds-demo.
Let's change the file one again.
Also, let's create a new file,
like file4.txt, new file for stash.
Now my feature branch already
has some uncommitted changes.
Now if I move to my master
branch, git checkout main,
I would be able to
successfully move to the main
branch and my changes also move with me.
So if I do get status, I
have all the changes which
I made on the feature
branch on the main branch.
Otherwise, what I could do was
simply go back to my feature branch.
I can choose to push the
changes into the stash.
One thing to note here is that git
stash, because I ran git stash push,
And let's check the git status.
So we have only pushed
the file one, but file four
was a newly created
file, so it was not pushed.
Let's pop the changes, and
let's try to push it again.
So if you want to push both
tracked and untracked files,
we want to push both file 4 and file 1.
So we can do it using git stash push .
This will also push your
untracked files in the stash.
So now I can go back to the main branch.
If I want to make any
changes to the main branch,
like we talked about a
bug. So let's do a bug fix.
Make the change.
Bug fix, git commit.
And now I can go back to my feature
branch where I was working before.
Git checkout features dash demo.
And I can apply back the changes.
So now I have the changes which I
made to my Stash demo feature branch.
So this is how you can use Stash Let's
see what happens if I commit these changes,
git add all, git commit, commit one.
I have committed my
changes on the feature branch.
Now I will make more changes.
Let's change the file one.
So now, when I try to move to main
branch, this will give me an error.
Your local changes to the following
files would be overwritten by checkout,
so please commit or stash
them before you switch branches.
And this is because file one has
a different text in this branch,
whereas file one has a
different text in main branch.
So we are not able to directly switch.
So of course we can do is git stash.
Push this time because it's
already an existing file.
We don't need to use minus you flag.
We can simply do get stash push.
We can go back to our main branch.
Do the fix or whatever we want to work on,
and then we can go back to
our feature branch and pop the
changes whenever we are done
working on the main branch.
So let's create another Bug fix 2.
Git add all. Git commit.
Bug to fix.
And now we can go back
to our feature branch.
Git checkout.
Stash demo.
Let's say I want to apply these
stashed changes to the main branch.
So let's stash these changes again.
And let's say I want to apply
these changes to another branch.
So we can go to the main branch,
and let's say I want to
apply it on the main branch.
So I will do git stash pop,
but this time there
will be conflicts Because
the stashed entry had a different
change, which was stash demo 2.
And the main branch had a different
text, which is bug fix bug fix 2.
So you can choose which
ones you want to apply.
Let's say we want to accept both changes.
And now you have.
Resolve the changes
because of the git stash pop.