What does squashing mean?
To squash in Git means to
combine multiple commits into one.
Let's say we want to combine C3,
C4, and C5 into a single commit.
Then we can use Git
squash to create a new commit,
which will be a
combination of C3, C4, and C5.
When you should squash commits,
it really depends on what
you have decided as a team.
Instead of many individual commits,
which might be unnecessary, with squashing,
you only get a single commit
appearing in your main commit history.
This can be helpful in
keeping commit history clean.
There are multiple ways
to squash your commits.
The first way is using interactive rebase.
We'll talk more on it in the
interactive rebase section.
The second one we have is using merge.
You can squash all the
commits of a feature
branch while merging into the main branch.
The main benefit of
this is that history stays
clean and there is no
automatic merge commit.
If you merge without squash,
Git will create a merge commit.
Another way to squash
is using pull request.
A lot of Git hosting platforms
like GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket,
they provide an option to squash the
commits when merging a pull request.
So there is an option when you
click on merge pull request,
and you can choose squash and merge.
This will merge and also
squash all the commits
of your feature branch
into a single commit.
Let's go back to our repository.
So let's start by creating a new branch,
git checkout, minus b, feature squash.
Let's make three commits
to this feature branch.
Squash commit one.
Let's also change the
file to squash file two.
Commit one.
Let's add the changes. Squash commit one.
Let's make two more commits.
And change the commit message.
One more commit, so we'll do
file three, commit three, git add,
and make the third commit.
Now when we do git log,
we have three commits that
we made, commit one,
commit two, commit three.
Now let's say I want to merge this
feature branch into my main branch.
So for that, I will have
to go back to the main
branch We can do it using
checkout command, get checkout main.
We are on main branch.
Now in order to merge, we need to
run the merge command with git merge,
name of the branch, which is feed squash.
Now with merge, you can use a
flag, hyphen hyphen squash.
Now what squash does is that it brings
all the changes to your working directory.
So now all the changes related to those
three commits are in your working directory,
but you need to commit them.
Now there are two ways
how you can commit them.
One way is that you can simply do
commit and provide your own commit message.
This is a combination
of Last three commits.
Or what you can do is just use git commit.
And this time git
created an automatic message
which says squashed
commit of the following,
which contains squash commit
three, commit two, commit one.
So git also automatically
generates a message for you.
You can use the same one or you
can write your own commit message.
So let's use the same one. And now when
you do Git log, you have just one commit,
which is the squashed commit
of the following three commits.
So this is how you can
squash while merging.
Another way to do it
is using pull request.
Let's see how we can
do using pull request.
For that, let's create
a new feature branch.
Get checkout minus B,
feature squash using pull request.
Let's make the changes again.
Let's make three more commits again.
Squash with pull request.
Commit one.
Let's commit the changes.
Let's make two more commits.
Git add all, git commit.
Last commit, git add all.
Git commit.
Okay, so we have made
now three more commits.
Let's change the commit
message of the last commit because
I accidentally choose
the same commit message.
Git commit hyphen hyphen amend.
And now we have three commits.
Commit three, commit two, commit one.
Now this time we want to merge
using pull request and also squash.
So first thing we need to do is
we need to push this pull request,
squash pull request
feature branch to remote,
and for that we need to do git
push minus u, the branch name.
I have to use minus u flag because this
branch right now does not exist on remote.
Okay, just try git push
and use the same command.
So now our feature
branch is already pushed
and there's a link to create pull request.
Let's go to this link.
Let's create a pull request,
squash demo using pull requests.
Best description. And then
click on create pull request.
OK, this branch has some
conflicts which needs to be resolved.
Let's resolve using.
GitHub this time.
Let's accept our changes on
this branch and mark as resolved.
Commit the resolved changes.
So this time I just resolved using
GitHub, but if you have conflicts, you need to,
you can also resolve
using your command line.
So now this time, before
clicking on merge request,
I will click on this arrow
and it says squash and merge.
So let's do the squash and merge.
And now it gives you an option
to change the message as well.
So I can do squash
demo with pull requests.
Okay, let's verify the
changes in our main branch.
Let's go back to our
repository and then do git pull.
Now we do Git log, and we
can see we have the commit
from the branch that we
merged from the pull request.
So this is how you can merge along
with squashing using pull request.