What is an interactive rebase?
Interactive rebase allows you
to rewrite the commit history.
With interactive rebase, you can do a
bunch of things like changing commit messages.
You can also combine multiple
commits, which is squashing.
Then you can also split
and edit existing commits.
You can reorder commits
or even delete commits.
You can also change a commit message
using amend command, but with amend,
you can only amend the last commit.
Interactive rebase allows you to
reword any commit in your Git history.
You can use the reword
keyword to change the message.
This is how it looks on your screen,
that you can use reword and
change the commit message.
You can combine multiple
commits using squash keyword.
In order to open the
screen with interactive rebase,
run command git rebase
minus i head tilde n.
N here also refers to how many
commits you want to go back from head.
You can also delete
commits with Interactive Rebase.
In order to delete a
commit, use drop keyword.
Let's see how
everything looks in practice.
We would be amending
commits, squashing commits,
and deleting commits
using Interactive Rebase.
Let's go back to our repository.
Let me here just make three commits.
Interactive rebase commit one,
git add all, git commit minus m,
interactive rebase commit one.
Let's make two more commits.
We need to add it and then make a commit.
And the third commit with
git add all and git commit.
Let's verify our commits.
So now we have commit one,
commit two, and commit three.
Now I want to change the
message of second last commit.
Remember that if you want to change
the commit message of last commit,
you can use amend command as well.
But since we want to change the
message of second last commit,
we can use interactive rebase.
In order to change the message of
second last commit, move one commit before,
which is this commit, copy the hash,
And now open interactive rebase
screen with git rebase, minus i,
minus i is for interactive,
and paste the copied hash.
Now you see your last two commits,
and we wanted to change
the message for commit to.
You can do it using reword keyboard.
So let's change pic to reword.
Click Escape, colon, WQ.
So now Interactive Rebase asks
you to change the commit message.
Enter your new commit message. Press I,
and Interactive Rebase reverted commit.
Let's save it, and let's
verify in the git log.
So see, we have changed the
message of second last commit,
and now it says
interactive rebase reworded commit.
In order to open the interactive
rebase screen, you can also use head.
Let's say now I want to change the
commit message of third last commit,
so I need to go Either I can do is
copy the hash of one commit before,
or what I can do is I can say
get rebase minus I head three.
This means go three commits before head.
So now you can see
your last three commits,
and we want to change the
commit message of the first commit.
So let's check reword, escape
wq, and let's change this as well.
Interactive rebase, escape wq.
Now let's verify in Git log, and we have
changed the message of third last commit.
So this is how you can
use interactive rebase
to change the messages of your commits.
Now let's see how we can use
interactive rebase to squash our commits.
We can play with the same commits.
Now let's say I want to squash all
three commits, commit one, commit two,
and commit three into a single commit.
So first thing we need to do
is open the interactive rebase.
So we copy the commit, one commit
before, or we can also use head.
In order to open interactive rebase,
click on right, get rebase minus I, head,
because we want to squash
our last three commits.
So I'm saying go three commits before.
Now I can see all of
my last three commits.
And here, let's say I
want to squash my second
and third commit on
top of my first commit.
So this commit one should also have
commit two and commit three files.
In order to squash, change the squash.
Change pick to squash
for third commit as well.
What this will do is that it
will combine the two commits
with the squash into
the one which is picked.
Press escape, colon, wq.
Now here, what you can also do here
is you can provide your own message,
or you can simply use the git message.
I'm going to use the same
default one provided by git.
And now here you can say git log,
and it says that you have interactive
rebase commit one, the second commit,
which we reworded, and
third commit as well.
So now it has created the combination of
last three commits into the single commit.
Last thing we want to also
practice is dropping commit.
So let's make two more commits.
Drop commit one.
Get add all.
Get commit minus m. Drop one.
Let's make two commits, git
add all, git commit drop two.
Let's verify these commits in the git log
command. So we have drop one and drop two.
Let me now delete this commit.
In order to do that, go to one
commit before, or you can also use head,
but let's copy this hash, open
interactive rebase, get rebase, minus i, commit hash.
Now we want to drop the second
commit, so let's choose drop, colon wq,
Let's go to Git log and verify.
So now you can see the
second last commit which
we made dropped to, it has been removed.
So this is how you can use interactive
rebase to change the message of your commit.
Then you can also do
squashing using interactive rebase.
And finally, you can also delete
commits using interactive rebase.