What is a Git reflog?
Git reflog is basically a log
of all of your actions in Git.
For example, switching
branches or making commits.
This makes it easy to undo
any action with git reflog,
like restoring accidentally deleted
commits or restoring a deleted branch.
The log is maintained
in chronological order
so that you can easily view your actions.
This is how it looks with the Git
reflog. When you run Git reflog,
it shows you Your actions,
for example, checkout, you
move to another branch,
or you made any commit.
Git replog is different than git log.
Git log is basically
history of your commits.
It shows you all your commits along
with the metadata about the commits.
Git log is different than Git reflog.
Git log represents the
history of your commits,
whereas Git reflog
shows you a private record
of your actions in your Git repository.
This is really specific to your
workspace, showing your local commits.
We can use git reflog to store lost
commits and also to restore deleted branches.
In order to restore lost commits, you
need to run command git reflog, find a hash,
one previous to the reset entry, This is
the commit, which has your deleted changes.
So you need to check out to that hash
and then create a branch from that commit.
Finally, you will have the lost
commit in the newly created branch,
and you can cherry pick the
commit in your main feature branch.
You can also restore a deleted branch.
In order to do that, do the same thing.
Run command git reflog.
Go through the reflog entries to
find reference of the deleted branch.
Once you find the hash,
you can do the same thing.
Just copy the hash, and then
create a new branch from that commit.
Let's practice both the things together.
So first we want to restore the commits,
and then we want to
restore the deleted branches.
Let's go back to our
repository, and here let's make A commit,
let me see git reflog demo1.
I will make this commit.
git commit-m reflog commit1.
Now I'm going to remove this commit.
So we have made the
commit for reflog commit one.
I want to delete this commit.
And how we can do this, how we can
delete any commit is using git reset command.
So I can copy the hash one before.
And then do git reset hyphen hyphen hard
and the commit where I want to reset to.
This will move me to
the second last commit,
and I will not have any changes related
to the last commit in my working directory.
Now you can see I have
permanently lost those changes.
I don't have my last
commit changes anymore.
What if I want to
recover this lost commit?
So let's start with the git
reflog command, use git reflog.
And this is the command
when I did the git reset.
So I want to move to hash
one before the reset command.
It's this one.
Now I will do git checkout to this commit.
Now, remember when I check out to any
commit, we are in a detached head state.
So we need to create a branch from here.
Let's create a new branch,
checkout-b, recover commit.
Now I'm in this recovered commit
branch, but when I do git log,
I do have my commit, which I lost.
So I can simply copy the hash, go back
to the main branch, git checkout main.
And now I can do cherry
pick and type the commit hash.
With cherry pick, I can move the
commit from one branch to another branch.
So now when I run git
log, I see the commit.
Which I lost back into my main branch.
So this is really useful if you
accidentally delete a commit and you want it back.
So you can use git reflog
to recover your lost commit.
Now let's see how we can
recover our deleted branches.
First of all, let's create a new branch.
Rebase delete branch.
Sorry, reflog delete branch.
Let's make a couple of commits here. You
get commit minus m, reflog commit two.
And commit three.
Get add all, get
commit, reflog commit three.
Let's verify our commit history. So
we have reflog commit two and three,
which we have made to this branch.
Now let's go back to main and
I'm going to delete this branch.
You can delete a branch with git
branch minus capital D and the branch name.
So now if I verify from the
branch list, I don't have any branch.
Related to reflog delete branch.
You can also verify by moving it
by trying to move to this branch,
but it will give you an error that this
did not match any files known to git.
So because this branch does not exist.
Now let's see how we can
recover deleted branches.
Firstly, let's create a new branch, git
checkout minus b reflog delete branch.
Let's make two commits on this branch,
git add all, git commit, minus m, reflog,
delete branch, commit one.
Let's make another commit.
Git reflog, minus am, commit to.
So now we have Reflog, delete
branch commit one and commit two,
which we have made on this branch.
Let's go to the main branch.
And delete this branch.
So we'll do git branch minus
capital D and the branch name.
Now let's verify if this branch
exists or not with git checkout.
Okay, we get an error, so
this branch is deleted.
You can also verify by
running git branch command,
and it will display the
list of branches you have.
Clearly, we don't find
the reflog delete command.
Reflog delete branch.
So let's see how we can recover this.
So firstly we need to do git reflog.
Now here, find the entry
where you can find your branch.
So here I need to find the git.
So this is reflog delete branch.
This is the entry for the
delete branch, which I created.
And I also made two more commits on it.
So ideally, if I move to this hash,
I would have all these two entries.
So I can do is I can
copy this hash, and then
I can do git checkout, move to this hash.
And let's create the
branch with the same name.
Reflog, delete branch.
So now we have recovered the
branch along with all the commits.
So this is how you can recover your
deleted branches with Git reflog.