To recap what we learned in this
lesson, so first we talked about stash,
and we learned how to
stash and unstash commits.
Then we also saw different
ways to squash our commits.
Squashing is basically
combining multiple commits into one.
Then we talked about interactive rebase,
and we saw the powers
of interactive rebase,
that we can use interactive rebase for
amending, squashing, and deleting commits.
Finally, we talked about git reflog,
and we saw how we can recover our
deleted commits and deleted branches.
Now moving to the exercise part.
As an exercise for part
one, create a feature branch.
You can call it anything
or feature git advanced.
Make three commits to the branch.
Change the commit message
of the second last commit.
Also, squash the last two
commits and verify using
git log if everything
is changed correctly.
As a part two, make a commit,
delete the commit using hard reset,
and then try to
recover the deleted commit.