We have covered a lot of ground in this
course, and now that we are wrapping up,
you should feel
confident using Git like a pro.
From basics to advanced features,
you have learned how to
effectively manage your projects
using one of the most
popular version control system.
Let's take a moment to recap all
the key topics we have explored.
In the first lesson, we
started with an overview of version
control and got
familiar with Git and GitHub.
We set up Git, learned key terminologies,
and understood the basics of
pushing code to a remote repository.
In the second lesson, we focused on
how to use Git in your daily workflow,
including adding and committing
files, fetching, pulling changes,
and working from both the command
line and graphical user interface.
We then moved on to mastering
commits in the third lesson.
Here we learned how to create
well-structured commits, amend commits,
write meaningful commit messages, and
compare changes using git diff command.
In the fourth lesson, we took a
deeper look at undoing changes,
covering essential commands like
git checkout, git restore, git reset,
and git revert to help you roll
back or adjust your work as needed.
The fifth lesson
introduced us to branches and tags,
where we explored how to create and
manage branches, delete and rename them,
and implement effective
branching strategies.
We also learned how to tag specific points
in the repository,
especially for releases.
In the sixth lesson, we
tackled merging and rebasing,
understanding the theory behind
each, practicing both the techniques,
and learning how to handle conflicts.
We also touched on creating
pull requests for collaboration.
Finally, in the seventh lesson,
we explored some Git advanced features
like Git stash for saving work in progress,
squashing commits to clean up commit
history, using interactive rebase,
and tracking changes with Git reflog.
And that's the course. Thank you for
joining me in this journey to master Git.
I hope now you feel equipped to
use Git confidently in your project.